<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://codexfelis.github.io/flumen/index.html</id>
    <title>Flumen: Digital Humanities News Aggregator</title>
    <updated>2021-08-26T15:45:26.948Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codexfelis.github.io/flumen/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://codexfelis.github.io/flumen/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Parima digihumanitaaria-alase lõputöö stipendium (600 eurot)]]></title>
        <id>32349 at http://digihum.ut.ee</id>
        <link href="http://digihum.ut.ee/event/parima-digihumanitaaria-alase-l%C3%B5put%C3%B6%C3%B6-stipendium-600-eurot"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T21:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Statuut



	Digihumanitaaria ja Infoühiskonna Keskus kuulutab välja konkursi 2020/21. õa parima digihumanitaaria-alase lõputöö (bakalaureuse- või magistritöö) leidmiseks.



	Lõputöö peab vastama järgmistele tingimustele ehk see:



Loe lähemalt Parima digihumanitaaria-alase lõputöö stipendium (600 eurot) kohta]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>a71389</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GLAM Workbench – a platform for digital HASS research]]></title>
        <id>http://wragge.micro.blog/2021/08/26/glam-workbench-a.html</id>
        <link href="https://updates.timsherratt.org/2021/08/26/glam-workbench-a.html"/>
        <updated>2021-08-26T06:31:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re in the midst of planning for the HASS Research Data Commons, which will deliver some much-needed investment in digital research infrastructure for the humanities and social sciences. Amongst the funded programs are tools for text analysis as part of the Linguistics Data Commons, and a platform for more advanced research using Trove. I’m hoping that this will be an opportunity to take stock of existing tools and resources, and build flexible pathways for researchers that enable them to collect, move, analyse, preserve, and share data across different platforms and services.
To this end, I thought it might be useful to try and summarise what the GLAM Workbench offers, particularly for Trove researchers. The GLAM Workbench doesn’t really have an institutional home, and is mostly unfunde…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Sherratt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Teaching available at KCL Digital Humanities – digital skills needed]]></title>
        <id>https://blogs.kcl.ac.uk/ddh/?p=3106</id>
        <link href="https://blogs.kcl.ac.uk/ddh/2021/08/24/teaching-available-at-kcl-digital-humanities-digital-skills-needed/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-24T12:14:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Department of Digital Humanities at King’s College London is looking for hourly paid lecturers to teach introductory computational skills on the weekly seminars of our digital culture modules in person at our Strand campus. In addition to computational skills, we also have some modules open for which a conceptual knowledge of machine learning and data … 
Continue reading "Teaching available at KCL Digital Humanities – digital skills needed"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mercedes Bunz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New article: “Journalism aggregators: an analysis of Longform.org”]]></title>
        <id>https://blogs.kcl.ac.uk/ddh/?p=3109</id>
        <link href="https://blogs.kcl.ac.uk/ddh/2021/08/24/new-article-journalism-aggregators/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-24T07:26:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An article on “Journalism aggregators: an analysis of Longform.org” co-authored by Marco Braghieri, Tobias Blanke and Jonathan Gray has just been published in Journalism Research. The article is open access and available in both English and German. Here’s the abstract: What is the role and significance of digital long-form content aggregators in contemporary journalism? This … 
Continue reading "New article: “Journalism aggregators: an analysis of Longform.org”"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan Gray</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CfP: Sammler*innen, Sammlung, Netz]]></title>
        <id>node/709</id>
        <link href="https://dig-hum.de/aktuelles/cfp-sammlerinnen-sammlung-netz"/>
        <updated>2021-08-23T15:13:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sammler*innen, Sammlung, Netz. Zu den Netzimplikationen von Sammlungspraxis und Sammlungsforschung 
von: Jörn Münkner, Joëlle Weis, Maximilian Görmar Tagung an der Herzog August…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>406</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jisc licence subscriptions manager now live for Liverpool University Press Opening the Future initiative]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rluk.ac.uk/?p=10647</id>
        <link href="https://lup.openingthefuture.net/news/12/#new_tab"/>
        <updated>2021-08-23T11:06:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Liverpool University Press (LUP) and the COPIM project are pleased to announce a partnership with Jisc on their Opening the Future membership programme. The recent agreement means that UK libraries can now easily sign up and pay for two packages of books on offer from LUP through Jisc’s Licence Subscription Manager: https://subscriptionsmanager.jisc.ac.uk/catalogue/2651. Access to two [...]
The post Jisc licence subscriptions manager now live for Liverpool University Press Opening the Future initiative appeared first on Research Libraries UK.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Melanie Cheung</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Family History Month experiment – search millions of name records from GLAM organisations]]></title>
        <id>http://wragge.micro.blog/2021/08/23/a-family-history.html</id>
        <link href="https://updates.timsherratt.org/2021/08/23/a-family-history.html"/>
        <updated>2021-08-23T00:05:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s a lot of rich historical data contained within the indexes that Australian GLAM organisations provide to help people navigate their records. These indexes, often created by volunteers, allow access by key fields such as name, date or location. They aid discovery, but also allow new forms of analysis and visualisation. Kate Bagnall and I wrote about some of the possibilities, and the difficulties, in this recently published article.
Many of these indexes can be downloaded from government data portals. The GLAM Workbench demonstrates how these can be harvested, and provides a list of available datasets to browse. But what’s inside them? The GLAM CSV Explorer visualises the contents of the indexes to give you a sneak peek and encourage you to dig deeper.
There’s even more indexes avai…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Sherratt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Balti digimeetodite suvekool / Baltic Summer School of Digital Humanities "Digital Methods in Humanities and Social Sciences"]]></title>
        <id>33298 at http://digihum.ut.ee</id>
        <link href="http://digihum.ut.ee/event/balti-digimeetodite-suvekool"/>
        <updated>2021-08-22T21:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Asukoht: 

Tallinn; online



 Loe lähemalt Balti digimeetodite suvekool / Baltic Summer School of Digital Humanities "Digital Methods in Humanities and Social Sciences" kohta]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>a71389</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Laura  Eckstein]]></title>
        <id>1137 at https://pricelab.sas.upenn.edu</id>
        <link href="https://pricelab.sas.upenn.edu/fellows/eckstein-laura"/>
        <updated>2021-08-20T16:52:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Academic Title: 

Fourth Year Ph.D. Student, History



Laura Newman Eckstein is a fouth-year Ph.D. student in history at the University of Pennsylvania. Her studies focus on Jews in the Atlantic world (17th-19th centuries) with specific interests in trade networks, material culture, book history, gender, race and digital humanities methodologies. Prior to her doctoral studies, she worked as the Judaica Digital Humanities Coordinator at the University of Pennsylvania Libraries. She holds a bachelor’s degree with the highest honors in religion from Haverford College. Eckstein’s senior thesis at Haverford focused on Jewish peddlers, their business networks, and their religious practices along the Lower Mississippi River between 1820-1865. She is the recipient of a 2014 Tri-College, Mellon Foundation Digital Humanities Fellowship where she where she worked with Professor Ryan Cordell in his lab for Viral Maps, Texts and Networks at Northeastern University, mapping the spread and reprinting of 19th-century newspapers and magazines. Eckstein is also the recipient of a John B. Hurford Arts and Humanities Center Summer Research Fellowship.


Fellowship Date: 

August, 2021—August, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>svarner@upenn.edu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RLUK CSN: Plan B – What’s the Big Deal event]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rluk.ac.uk/?p=10633</id>
        <link href="https://www.rluk.ac.uk/rluk-csn-plan-b-whats-the-big-deal-event/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-19T09:39:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On 18 August 2021 the RLUK CSN hosted a meeting on Plan B - What's the Big Deal? The event explored many aspects of ‘Plan B’ planning for content access and brought together key pieces of work going on across the sector. Discussion topics included alternative access methods including interlibrary loan and OA discovery, modelling and [...]
The post RLUK CSN: Plan B – What’s the Big Deal event appeared first on Research Libraries UK.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Melanie Cheung</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Becoming a Library Director]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rluk.ac.uk/?p=10587</id>
        <link href="https://www.rluk.ac.uk/becoming-a-library-director/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-17T13:41:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[RLUK’s New Director Network (NDN) was formed a few years ago as an informal grouping bringing together people who had recently become Library Directors at RLUK member institutions. It acts as a peer network for those newly appointed. Recently the network welcomed a new member who, when thinking about navigating the first few months [...]
The post Becoming a Library Director appeared first on Research Libraries UK.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Melanie Cheung</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mehrere Stellenangebote im INF-Projekt des SFB 1475]]></title>
        <id>node/708</id>
        <link href="https://dig-hum.de/aktuelles/mehrere-stellenangebote-im-inf-projekt-des-sfb-1475"/>
        <updated>2021-08-17T12:49:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Der geplante SFB 1475 „Metaphern der Religion“ vereint religionswissenschaftliche, philologische und linguistische Forschungen zur Bedeutung von Metaphern für die religiöse…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>406</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DHA2021 Goes Fully Virtual]]></title>
        <id>https://aa-dh.org/?p=418</id>
        <link href="https://aa-dh.org/2021/08/17/dha2021-goes-fully-virtual/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-17T06:50:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DHA2021 Call For Proposals The Australasian Association for Digital Humanities (aaDH) is pleased to invite proposals for posters, short papers, long papers, multi-paper panels and workshops, for DHA2021 (our COVID-delayed conference formerly known as DHA2020). DHA2021 will be a virtual conference running from 22-25 November 2021 (New Zealand time zone). Proposals from any country will … Continue reading "DHA2021 Goes Fully Virtual"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tully Barnett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Explore Trove’s digitised books]]></title>
        <id>http://wragge.micro.blog/2021/08/16/explore-troves-digitised.html</id>
        <link href="https://updates.timsherratt.org/2021/08/16/explore-troves-digitised.html"/>
        <updated>2021-08-16T05:40:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Trove books section of the GLAM Workbench has been updated! There’s freshly-harvested data, as well as updated Python packages, integration with Reclaim Cloud, and automated Docker builds.
Included is a notebook to harvest details of all books available from Trove in digital form. This includes both digitised books, that have been scanned and OCRd, as well as born digital publications, such as PDFs and epubs. The definition of ‘books’ is pretty loose – I’ve harvested details of anything that has been assigned the format ‘Book’ in Trove, but this includes ephemera, such as posters, pamphlets, and advertising.
In the latest harvest, I ended up with details of 42,174 ‘books’. This includes some duplicates, because multiple metadata entries can point to the same digital object. I thought it was best to preserve the duplicates, rather than discard the metadata.
Once I’d harvested the details of the books, I tried to see if there was any OCRd text available for download. If there was, I saved it to a public folder on CloudStor. In total, I was able to download 26,762 files of OCRd text.

The easiest way to explore the books is using this searchable database. It’s created using Datasette and is running on Glitch. Full text search is available on the ‘title’ and ‘contributors’ fields, and you can filter on things like date, copyright status, number of pages, and whether OCRd text is available for download. If there is OCRd text, a direct link to the file on CloudStor is included. You can use the database to filter the titles, creating your own dataset that you can download in CSV or JSON format.
If you just want the full list of books as a CSV file, you can download it here. And if you want all the OCRd text, you can go straight to the public folder on CloudStor – there’s about 3.6gb of text files to explore! #dhhacks]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Sherratt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Editors' Note: August 2021]]></title>
        <id>918e07ef-7e71-4a6b-9a71-420a83a766e8</id>
        <link href="https://reviewsindh.pubpub.org/pub/ed-note-august-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-08-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Editors' note on the August 2021 issue of Reviews in Digital Humanities, guest edited by Mary Caton Lingold]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Roopika Risam</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Gulu SoundTracks]]></title>
        <id>9241c6f8-ac9a-472c-b120-c923703a81c4</id>
        <link href="https://reviewsindh.pubpub.org/pub/gulusoundtracks"/>
        <updated>2021-08-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A review of Gulu SoundTracks, a collection of audio tracks that invites listeners into the sonic habitus and imaginations of their Gulu-based creators, created by Joella Bitter]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damascus Kafumbe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: .break .dance]]></title>
        <id>c62a7450-5479-4f95-a7e1-4f539134c69a</id>
        <link href="https://reviewsindh.pubpub.org/pub/breakdance"/>
        <updated>2021-08-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A review of .break .dance, an interactive choreo-essay on Black diasporic existence, created by Marisa Parham]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brittnay L. Proctor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Sound Never Tasted So Good]]></title>
        <id>c6a2b438-8034-4732-bce5-84f60df0fa41</id>
        <link href="https://reviewsindh.pubpub.org/pub/sound-never-tasted-so-good"/>
        <updated>2021-08-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A review of Sound Never Tasted So Good, a project that explores how the senses work together in gustatory experiences, created by Steph Ceraso]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>KC Hysmith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A miscellany of ephemera, oddities, & estrays]]></title>
        <id>http://wragge.micro.blog/2021/08/13/a-miscellany-of.html</id>
        <link href="https://updates.timsherratt.org/2021/08/13/a-miscellany-of.html"/>
        <updated>2021-08-13T01:02:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m just in the midst of updating my harvest of OCRd text from Trove’s digitised books (more about that soon!). But amongst the items catalogued as ‘books’ are a wide assortment of ephemera, posters, advertisements, and other oddities. There’s no consistent way of identifying these items through the search interface, but because I’ve found the number of pages in each ‘book’ as part of the harvesting process, I can limit results to items with just a single digitised page – there’s more than 1,500! To make it easy to explore this collection of odds and ends, I’ve downloaded all the single page images and compiled them into one big PDF with links back to their entries in Trove. Enjoy your browsing!

This is another example of the ways in which we can extend and enrich existing collection interfaces using simple technologies like PDFs and CSVs. We can create slices across existing categories to expose interesting features, and provide new entry points for researchers. Some other examples in the GLAM Workbench are the collection of editorial cartoons from The Bulletin, the list of Trove newspapers with non-English content, the harvest of ABC Radio National programs, and the recent collection of politicians talking about COVID. Let me know if you have any ideas for additional slices! #dhhacks]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Sherratt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zita C. Nunes]]></title>
        <id>1136 at https://pricelab.sas.upenn.edu</id>
        <link href="https://pricelab.sas.upenn.edu/fellows/nunes-zita"/>
        <updated>2021-08-12T14:04:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Academic Title: 

Associate Professor, English, University of Pennsylvania



Zita C. Nunes, Associate Professor of English, teaches and conducts research in the area of African American/African Diaspora literatures from a pan-African and multilingual perspective.The author of Cannibal Democracy: Race and Representation in the Literature of the Americas (Minnesota UP, 2008), she is completing a monograph, Racism in Translation: Multilingualism, Comparative Literature, the Harlem Renaissance, and a bilingual digital edition of the Correio de África, a Black newspaper published in Lisbon, Portugal between 1921 and 1924. 


Fellowship Date: 

August, 2021—September, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>milinski@upenn.edu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jessa  Lingel]]></title>
        <id>1135 at https://pricelab.sas.upenn.edu</id>
        <link href="https://pricelab.sas.upenn.edu/fellows/lingel-jessa"/>
        <updated>2021-08-12T13:43:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Academic Title: 

Associate Professor, Communication, University of Pennsylvania



Jessa Lingel is an associate professor at the Annenberg School for Communication and core faculty in the Gender, Sexuality and Women’s Studies Program at the University of Pennsylvania.  She received her PhD in communication and information from Rutgers University.  She has an MLIS from Pratt Institute and an MA in gender studies from New York University.  Her research interests include digital inequalities and technological distributions of power. Using qualitative methods, Lingel studies how marginalized and countercultural groups use and reshape digital media.


Fellowship Date: 

August, 2021—August, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>milinski@upenn.edu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exploring ideas for our Living with Machines exhibition]]></title>
        <id>https://livingwithmachines.ac.uk/?p=1960</id>
        <link href="https://livingwithmachines.ac.uk/exploring-ideas-for-our-living-with-machines-exhibition/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=exploring-ideas-for-our-living-with-machines-exhibition"/>
        <updated>2021-08-11T18:18:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An exhibition has been part of our plans since we began working on the funding bid that became Living with Machines in 2017 or so. In 2020 we began work in earnest on finding collaborators, finding dates at a suitable venue and thinking about how we could translate research findings from Living with Machines into […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mia Ridge</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting to Know CARE: Partnering Organization to Creativity in the Time of COVID-19 Project]]></title>
        <id>https://dhlc.cal.msu.edu/?p=331</id>
        <link href="https://dhlc.cal.msu.edu/2021/08/11/getting-to-know-care-partnering-organization-to-creativity-in-the-time-of-covid-19-project/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-11T16:53:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Creativity in the Time of COVID-19 project explores the ways that people have used various forms of creativity to cope with the COVID-19 pandemic through a survey.  This Mellon Foundation grant initiative is titled, “Just Futures,” and has the intentions of shining light on the experiences of diverse and/or marginalized groups such as the […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>saamsuep</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pre and Post Pizza Poetry]]></title>
        <id>https://dhlc.cal.msu.edu/?p=321</id>
        <link href="https://dhlc.cal.msu.edu/2021/08/11/pre-and-post-pizza-poetry/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-11T16:35:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have never been much of a poet until a young student at the Refugee Development Center of Lansing asked me what poetry was. I told him, “It is when you play with words in a way that is not traditionally published.” He looked at me and it was evident that he was still unsure […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>carrmitc</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UKRI’s support for green open access is the right way forward]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rluk.ac.uk/?p=10553</id>
        <link href="https://www.timeshighereducation.com/blog/ukris-support-green-open-access-right-way-forward#new_tab"/>
        <updated>2021-08-11T09:44:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New guidelines have rightly rejected publisher claims that gold is the only sustainable path for open access, say Stephen Eglen and Rupert Gatti
The post UKRI’s support for green open access is the right way forward appeared first on Research Libraries UK.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Melanie Cheung</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Angelina   Eimannsberger]]></title>
        <id>1134 at https://pricelab.sas.upenn.edu</id>
        <link href="https://pricelab.sas.upenn.edu/fellows/eimannsberger-angelina-0"/>
        <updated>2021-08-10T14:47:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Academic Title: 

Ph.D. Candidate, Comparative Literature, University of Pennsylvania



Angelina Eimannsberger is a graduate student in the Comparative Literature department at the University of Pennsylvania. Eimannsberger's research focuses on contemporary US women writers, novels and life writing, feminist theory, Socialist Feminism, femininity, and queer theory, as well as women’s book clubs, and diverse re-tellings of Pride and Prejudice. Eimannsberger's Summer 2020 project involved an analysis of the female celebrity book club Reese's Book Club (hosted by actress and producer Reese Witherspoon and her company Hello Sunshine), its books and participants as well as bookish talk about the books, especially on Goodreads.
 


Fellowship Date: 

August, 2021—August, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>milinski@upenn.edu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Matthew  Aiello]]></title>
        <id>1133 at https://pricelab.sas.upenn.edu</id>
        <link href="https://pricelab.sas.upenn.edu/fellows/aiello-matthew"/>
        <updated>2021-08-10T13:27:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Academic Title: 

Ph.D. Candidate, English, University of Pennsylvania



Matthew Aiello is a Ph.D. Candidate in English at UPenn. His dissertation, Writing Under Duress: Trauma and Repetition in Early England, 1070-1270 treats trauma as a dynamic force that can be reconfigured as a tool of historical analysis for premodern texts while also exploring how trauma theory itself can be changed by the decentering agent of the premodern. His published work has appeared in Comitatus, Essays and Studies, Review of English Studies, and most recently in New Medieval Literatures. 


Fellowship Date: 

August, 2021]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>milinski@upenn.edu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sharing the benefits: free to view newspapers on the British Newspaper Archive]]></title>
        <id>https://livingwithmachines.ac.uk/?p=1942</id>
        <link href="https://livingwithmachines.ac.uk/sharing-the-benefits-free-to-view-newspapers-on-the-british-newspaper-archive/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=sharing-the-benefits-free-to-view-newspapers-on-the-british-newspaper-archive"/>
        <updated>2021-08-09T12:51:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are excited to announce a major milestone for newspapers digitised through this project – from today, some of the out of copyright newspapers we digitised are free to view on the British Newspaper Archive. We’re part of the first million free to view pages as part of this collaboration between the British Library and […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mia Ridge</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everyday heritage and the GLAM Workbench]]></title>
        <id>http://wragge.micro.blog/2021/08/09/everyday-heritage-and.html</id>
        <link href="https://updates.timsherratt.org/2021/08/09/everyday-heritage-and.html"/>
        <updated>2021-08-09T01:26:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some good news on the funding front with the success of the Everyday Heritage project in the latest round of ARC Linkage grants. The project aims to look beyond the formal discourses of ‘national’ heritage to develop a more diverse range of heritage narratives. Working at the intersection of place, digital collections, and material culture, team members will develop a series of ‘heritage biographies’, that document everyday experience, and provide new models for the heritage sector.

Digital methods will play a major role in the project. I’ll be leading the ‘Heritage Hacks’ work package that will support the creation of the heritage biographies and develop a range of new tools and tutorials for use in heritage management contexts. All the tools, methods, and data generated through the project will be documented using Jupyter notebooks and published through the GLAM Workbench. Watch this space!
The project is led by Tracy Ireland (University of Canberra), with Jane Lydon (UWA), Kate Bagnall (UTAS), and me as chief investigators. Our industry partner is GML Heritage.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Sherratt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ali  M.  Rahman]]></title>
        <id>1132 at https://pricelab.sas.upenn.edu</id>
        <link href="https://pricelab.sas.upenn.edu/fellows/rahman-ali"/>
        <updated>2021-08-06T17:17:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Academic Title: 

Lecturer, Critical Writing Program, University of Pennsylvania



Dr. Ali M. Rahman is a Lecturer in the Critical Writing Program at the University of Pennsylvania. Ali completed his Ph.D. at UC Santa Barbara focusing on Islamic oral traditions and education in the digital age. He has taught in the Middle East with refugee populations, the New York prison system, independent K-12 and boarding schools, and both public and private universities. His research focuses on digital writing, rhetoric, and pedagogy. He is currently working on a book exploring authority in online spaces and the search for knowledge in a neoliberal age.


Fellowship Date: 

August, 2021—September, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>milinski@upenn.edu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CfP: Materialität und Medialität: Aspekte einer anderen Ästhetik (März 2022, Tübingen)]]></title>
        <id>node/707</id>
        <link href="https://dig-hum.de/aktuelles/cfp-materialit%C3%A4t-und-medialit%C3%A4t-aspekte-einer-anderen-%C3%A4sthetik-m%C3%A4rz-2022-t%C3%BCbingen"/>
        <updated>2021-08-06T15:46:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Der Sonderforschungsbereich (SFB) 1391 „Andere Ästhetik“ untersucht ästhetische Akte und Artefakte der Vormoderne im Spannungsfeld von Gestaltungswissen und sozialer Praxis.…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>406</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Uploading the Exeter Book – A behind the scenes look at digitising a literary treasure]]></title>
        <id>https://digitalhumanities.exeter.ac.uk/?p=802</id>
        <link href="https://digitalhumanities.exeter.ac.uk/2021/08/uploading-the-exeter-book-a-behind-the-scenes-look-at-digitising-a-literary-treasure/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-06T09:32:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The new online platform for the Exeter book is now live, making one of the oldest surviving volumes of English literature in the world fully accessible to the public for the first time.   The new platform has already been generating lots of interest, especially through Exeter’s role as a UNESCO city of literature, and since […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Hopkin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RLUK welcomes publication of UKRI’s new Open Access Policy]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rluk.ac.uk/?p=10463</id>
        <link href="https://www.rluk.ac.uk/rluk-welcomes-publication-of-ukris-new-open-access-policy/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-06T08:03:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[RLUK welcomes the publication today of a new Open Access (OA) policy applying to research outputs that result from UKRI funding. The new policy is the result of an extensive consultation period during which the views of all relevant stakeholders - including the research library community and RLUK - were sought and heard. The new [...]
The post RLUK welcomes publication of UKRI’s new Open Access Policy appeared first on Research Libraries UK.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Melanie Cheung</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recent GLAM Workbench presentations]]></title>
        <id>http://wragge.micro.blog/2021/08/06/recent-glam-workbench.html</id>
        <link href="https://updates.timsherratt.org/2021/08/06/recent-glam-workbench.html"/>
        <updated>2021-08-06T07:42:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[So far this year I’ve given eight workshops or presentations relating to the GLAM Workbench, with probably a few more yet to come. Here’s the latest:
Introducing the GLAM Workbench, presentation for the Griffith University Centre for Social and Cultural Research, Digital Humanities Seminar Series, 6 August 2021
Exploring the GLAM Workbench (slides), presentation for the UTS Digital Histories Seminar Series, 8 July 2021
The GLAM Workbench: A Labs approach?, presentation for the panel ‘Research use of web archives: A labs approach’, at the IIPC Web Archiving Conference, 15 June 2021
Hands-on introduction to the GLAM Workbench, workshop for the Professional Historians Association of Victoria and Tasmania, 27 May 2021
Exploring collections through the GLAM Workbench, keynote presentation for the XVIII Congrés d’Arxvística i Gestió de Documents de Catalunya, 11 May 2021
Quick hacks and DIY data: Innovations for the discerning historian, presentation for AHA ECR digital skills seminar, 5 March 2021
You can view all the GLAM Workbench presentations here.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Sherratt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Updated! Lots and lots of text freshly harvested from Trove periodicals]]></title>
        <id>http://wragge.micro.blog/2021/08/06/updated-lots-and.html</id>
        <link href="https://updates.timsherratt.org/2021/08/06/updated-lots-and.html"/>
        <updated>2021-08-05T23:49:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For a few years now I’ve been harvesting downloadable text from digitised periodicals in Trove and making it easily available for exploration and research. I’ve just completed the latest harvest – here’s the summary:
1,163 digitised periodicals had text available for download
Text was downloaded from 51,928 individual issues
Adding up to a total of around 12gb of text
If you want to dive straight in, here’s a list of all the harvested periodicals, with links to download a summary of available issues, as well as all the harvested text (there’s one file per issue). You’ll notice that the list includes a large number of parliamentary papers and government reports as well as published journals.

All of the harvested text is available from a public folder on CloudStor.
The harvesting process involves a few different steps:
First I generate a list of periodicals available in digital form from Trove. This includes digitised titles, as well as born-digital titles submitted through e-Legal Deposit. This produced a CSV file containing the details of 7,270 titles. See this notebook for details.
Then I work through this list of titles to find out how many issues of each title are available through Trove. This information isn’t accessible through the API, so I have to do some screen scraping.
Next I work through the list of issues and try to download the text contents. Most of the born-digital titles don’t have downloadable text.
Once I’ve downloaded all the text I can from a title, I create a CSV file for it that lists the available issues and notes whether text is available for each. This file is stored with the text on CloudStor.
Once I’ve checked all the titles, I generate another CSV file that lists the details of all the periodicals that have downloadable text.
The code to harvest and document the downloaded text is available in this notebook. #dhhacks]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Sherratt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amanda   Licastro]]></title>
        <id>1131 at https://pricelab.sas.upenn.edu</id>
        <link href="https://pricelab.sas.upenn.edu/fellows/licastro-amanda"/>
        <updated>2021-08-05T19:17:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Academic Title: 

Emerging and Digital Literacy Designer, University of Pennsylvania



Dr. Amanda Licastro (she/her) is the Emerging and Digital Literacy Designer at the University of Pennsylvania, responsible for providing instructional design support in collaboration with other Library units and campus partners to ensure success of the critical literacies initiative. Amanda was formerly the Assistant Professor of Digital Rhetoric at Stevenson University in Maryland. Her research explores the intersection of technology and writing, including book history, dystopian literature, and digital humanities, with a focus on multimodal composition and Extended Reality. Amanda serves as the Director of Pedagogical Initiatives of the Book Traces project and is co-founder of the Journal of Interactive Technology and Pedagogy and the Writing Studies Tree. Publications include articles in Kairos, Digital Pedagogy in the Humanities, Hybrid Pedagogy, and Communication Design Quarterly, as well as chapters in Digital Reading and Writing in Composition Studies, and Critical Digital Pedagogy. Her co-edited collection, Composition and Big Data, is available for pre-order  from University of Pittsburgh Press. The grant-funded project on Virtual Reality Amanda developed and executed was awarded the Paul Fortier Prize at the 2017 Digital Humanities conference, and has been featured in the Baltimore Sun and Baltimore Magazine.


Fellowship Date: 

August, 2021—September, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>milinski@upenn.edu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[IIIF Conference 2021 sessions now available to view]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rluk.ac.uk/?p=10459</id>
        <link href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLYPP1-8uH9c6y-KUzicLQr_LkX8uaWa5h#new_tab"/>
        <updated>2021-08-05T12:46:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The IIIF Conference is intended for a wide range of participants, including digital image repository managers, content curators, software developers, scholars, and administrators at libraries, museums, and cultural heritage institutions, software firms, and other organisations working with digital images and audio/visual materials.
The post IIIF Conference 2021 sessions now available to view appeared first on Research Libraries UK.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Melanie Cheung</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Panel discussion: How libraries can support OA transitions of NFP publishers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rluk.ac.uk/?p=10456</id>
        <link href="https://www.rluk.ac.uk/panel-discussion-how-libraries-can-support-oa-transitions-of-nfp-publishers/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-05T12:30:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[RLUK Executive Director, David Prosser, participated in a panel discussion at the 2021 Liber Conference, on How libraries and consortia can support the OA transitions of not-for-profit publishers, and why. A recording of this session can be viewed below. Transformative OA agreements repurpose former subscription funds to support open access publishing, enabling more research [...]
The post Panel discussion: How libraries can support OA transitions of NFP publishers appeared first on Research Libraries UK.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Melanie Cheung</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elsevier lobbying UKRI last minute over funder’s OA policy (paywall)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rluk.ac.uk/?p=10454</id>
        <link href="https://www.researchprofessionalnews.com/rr-news-uk-open-access-2021-8-elsevier-lobbying-ukri-last-minute-over-funder-s-oa-policy/#new_tab"/>
        <updated>2021-08-05T12:14:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Head of research libraries consortium “concerned” over move “undermining” consultations on open access The publishing company Elsevier has made an eleventh-hour push to see its agenda better reflected in the forthcoming strategy on open access, to be published by the UK’s research funding agency, UK Research and Innovation.
The post Elsevier lobbying UKRI last minute over funder’s OA policy (paywall) appeared first on Research Libraries UK.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Melanie Cheung</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Helping small publishers help themselves, & libraries too – what institutions want to see in transformative OA proposals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rluk.ac.uk/?p=10447</id>
        <link href="https://www.rluk.ac.uk/helping-small-publishers-help-themselves-and-libraries-too-what-institutions-want-to-see-in-transformative-oa-proposals/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-05T11:43:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Earlier in the summer, Information Power published the report How to Enable Smaller Independent Publishers to Participate in OA Agreements. The report addresses some of the special challenges that smaller publishers face in terms of their lack of scale and the difficulties they can have in getting engagement with time-poor colleagues within libraries. We were [...]
The post Helping small publishers help themselves, & libraries too – what institutions want to see in transformative OA proposals appeared first on Research Libraries UK.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Melanie Cheung</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jobs: Lecturer in Digital Innovation Management Education]]></title>
        <id>https://blogs.kcl.ac.uk/ddh/?p=3100</id>
        <link href="https://blogs.kcl.ac.uk/ddh/2021/08/04/jobs-lecturer-in-digital-innovation-management-education/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-04T15:11:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our Department of Digital Humanities is seeking to appoint two Lecturers (Academic Education Pathway) in Digital Innovation Management to contribute to its teaching in this and related areas. The post-holder will have a sound knowledge of the key concepts, theories, debates and challenges in digital innovation management, information systems, algorithmic management and digital transformation, with … 
Continue reading "Jobs: Lecturer in Digital Innovation Management Education"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mercedes Bunz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mit romanistik.de schließt sich eine weitere Initiative unserem WissZeitG Statement an]]></title>
        <id>node/706</id>
        <link href="https://dig-hum.de/aktuelles/romanistikde-schlie%C3%9Ft-sich-eine-weitere-initiative-unserem-wisszeitg-statement"/>
        <updated>2021-08-04T11:49:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wir freuen uns, dass sich mit romantistik.de eine weitere Initiative unserer Stellungnahme zur Befristungspraxis an Hochschulen und außeruniversitären Forschungseinrichtungen in…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>406</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New models out!]]></title>
        <id>https://readcoop.eu/?p=26264</id>
        <link href="https://readcoop.eu/new-models-out/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-04T06:13:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Transkribus is happy to introduce new public models for Spanish and French. Álvaro Cuéllar of the ETSO “Estilometría aplicada al Teatro del Siglo de Oro” project  trained two models for theater manuscripts and theatre prints from the 17th and 18th century with the aim to modernize the spelling to the current rules. “The Spanish Golden […]
The post New models out! appeared first on READ-COOP.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Florian Stauder</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cassandra   Hradil]]></title>
        <id>1130 at https://pricelab.sas.upenn.edu</id>
        <link href="https://pricelab.sas.upenn.edu/fellows/hradil-cassandra"/>
        <updated>2021-08-03T18:09:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Academic Title: 

Digital Humanities Specialist



Cassandra serves as a liaison between the Center for Research Data & Digital Scholarship in the library and the Price Lab for Digital Humanities. She specializes in managing and supporting digital projects across a wide range of media. In her own practice, Cassandra is an artist, designer, programmer, and scholar who balances the critical with the creative. Her research and design interests include archival information systems, decolonial mapping, queer interfaces, e-textiles, and feminist data visualization. She is a designer and developer at the Immersive Realities Lab for the Humanities, and she teaches part-time at Parsons School of Design. She has a bachelor’s degree in American Studies and Classics from Amherst College, where she also received the Five College Certificate in Native American and Indigenous Studies. She holds an MFA in Design and Technology from Parsons School of Design.


Fellowship Date: 

August, 2021]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>milinski@upenn.edu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jared   Farmer]]></title>
        <id>1129 at https://pricelab.sas.upenn.edu</id>
        <link href="https://pricelab.sas.upenn.edu/fellows/farmer-jared-0"/>
        <updated>2021-08-03T18:03:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Academic Title: 

Professor and Chair of Graduate Studies, Department of History, University of Pennsylvania



Jared Farmer is Professor and Chair of Graduate Studies, Department of History, University of Pennsylvania. An environmental historian, Farmer has temporal expertise in the long nineteenth century, and regional expertise in the North American West. He has received fellowships and grants from institutions such as ACLS, NEH, and the Sloan Foundation. His book On Zion’s Mount: Mormons, Indians, and the American Landscape (Harvard, 2008) won the Francis Parkman Prize from the Society of American Historians. In 2014, the Dallas Institute presented him the Hiett Prize in the Humanities; in 2017, the Carnegie Corporation of New York named him an Andrew Carnegie Fellow; and in 2018, the American Academy in Berlin awarded him a Berlin Prize. His forthcoming book is a place-based planetary history of ancient trees and the problem of long-term thinking. Since coming to Penn in 2020, Farmer has begun a teaching and research project, "Petrosylvania," on regional fossil fuel history.


Fellowship Date: 

September, 2021—August, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>milinski@upenn.edu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chris   Mustazza]]></title>
        <id>1128 at https://pricelab.sas.upenn.edu</id>
        <link href="https://pricelab.sas.upenn.edu/fellows/mustazza-chris-0"/>
        <updated>2021-08-03T17:56:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Academic Title: 

Co-Director, PennSound Archive; IT Director, Penn's School of Arts & Science



Chris Mustazza is Co-Director of the PennSound Archive, IT Director in Penn's School of Arts & Sciences, and lecturer in English. His work focuses on experimental digital analyses of poetry recordings. He earned his Ph.D. from Penn's English department and a Master's in Computer and Information Technology from Penn's School of Engineering and Applied Sciences. His work has appeared or will in Digital Humanities Quarterly, boundary 2, and Oral Tradition, as well as in a number of edited volumes in English and in French. His current book manuscript is a history of the poetry audio archive and details the longstanding connection between poetry recordings and scientific labs meant for the study of dialects. He is a research fellow at the Linguistics Data Consortium.


Fellowship Date: 

September, 2021—August, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>milinski@upenn.edu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Member update – July 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rluk.ac.uk/?p=10437</id>
        <link href="https://www.rluk.ac.uk/member-update-july-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-03T13:55:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[July update  Below is a brief summary of the main activities undertaken by the RLUK Executive in July 2021.     RLUK announcements  Report published: The role of academic and research libraries as active participants and leaders in the production of scholarly research Research Libraries UK is delighted to publish [...]
The post Member update – July 2021 appeared first on Research Libraries UK.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Melanie Cheung</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building a Transatlantic Digital Scholarship Skills Exchange for Research Libraries: Moving Forward]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rluk.ac.uk/?p=10427</id>
        <link href="https://www.rluk.ac.uk/building-a-transatlantic-digital-scholarship-skills-exchange-for-research-libraries-moving-forward/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-03T11:00:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There may be an ocean between the US and the UK, but in the age of Zoom, collaboration can transcend geographical boundaries. Research Libraries UK’s Digital Scholarship Network (DSN) and CLIR’s Digital Library Federation’s Data and Digital Scholarship (DDS) working group are continuing to foster a partnership aimed at building transatlantic collaborations and connections. The [...]
The post Building a Transatlantic Digital Scholarship Skills Exchange for Research Libraries: Moving Forward appeared first on Research Libraries UK.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Melanie Cheung</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[J.D.   Porter]]></title>
        <id>1127 at https://pricelab.sas.upenn.edu</id>
        <link href="https://pricelab.sas.upenn.edu/fellows/porter-jd-0"/>
        <updated>2021-08-02T19:59:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Academic Title: 

Digital Humanities Specialist



J.D. Porter is a DH Project Specialist at the Price Lab. He received his PhD in English from Stanford University in 2017 and then worked as the Associate/Technical Director at the Stanford Literary Lab. He specializes in text mining, American modernism, and race and ethnicity theory, with occasional forays into jazz studies, network analysis, and ordinary language philosophy. His work has appeared in (or is slated to appear in) Episteme, Cultural Analytics, the pamphlet series of the Stanford Literary Lab, and the edited volumes Ralph Ellison in Context and The Cambridge Companion to the American Short Story.


Fellowship Date: 

September, 2021—August, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>milinski@upenn.edu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Laying the foundations of a modern city. Middle-classes/Bourgeoisie and entrepreneurship in early 20th century Esch-sur-Alzette (1900-1940)]]></title>
        <id>3535 at https://www.c2dh.uni.lu</id>
        <link href="https://www.c2dh.uni.lu/events/laying-foundations-modern-city-middle-classesbourgeoisie-and-entrepreneurship-early-20th"/>
        <updated>2021-08-02T07:47:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Longtime associated with its working-class history, the ”Red Esch” was also composed of a diversified bourgeoisie, as well as of a thriving middle-class.
This research attempts to provide for the first comprehensive class and cultural history, focusing exclusively on the middle-classes and bourgeoisie of early 20th century Esch-sur-Alzette.
Who were the members of the middle and upper classes? Where did they come from? What were their professional occupations? Which space, whether social, commercial and residential did they occupy within the city? In which ways did they contribute to the urban development, improvement and embellishment of Esch-sur-Alzette?
Through her presentation, Suzana Cascao  will introduce the audience to the work in progress, i.e, the ways in which she designed her research (including sources and methodology), conceptual issues, research questions, its limitations and goals.
 
Wednesday, 15 September 2021
14.00 - 15.00
Online - Webex
If you want to participate, please send an e-mail to vanessa.napolitano@uni.lu to receive the link.
15 September 2021
  Contemporary history of Luxembourg
  Remixing Industrial Pasts in the Digital Age: Sounds, Images, Ecologies, Practices and Materialities in Space and Time
  Cultural studies  Regional history
  Research seminars
  Published  
    Hide image in content detail]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Noëlle Schon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New dataset – Politicians talking about COVID]]></title>
        <id>http://wragge.micro.blog/2021/08/02/new-dataset-politicians.html</id>
        <link href="https://updates.timsherratt.org/2021/08/02/new-dataset-politicians.html"/>
        <updated>2021-08-02T00:23:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Trove Journals section of the GLAM Workbench includes a notebook that helps you download press releases, speeches, and interview transcripts by Australian federal politicians. These documents are compiled and published by the Parliamentary Library, and the details are regularly harvested into Trove.
Using this notebook, I’ve created a collection of documents that include the words ‘COVID’ or ‘Coronavirus’. It includes all the metadata from Trove, as well as the full text of each document downloaded from the Parliamentary Library. There’s 3,995 documents in total, covering the period up until early April 2021. You can download them all as a zip file (12 mb).

While I was compiling this dataset, I also made a few improvements to the notebook. You can now filter the results to weed out false positives, and identify duplicates. #dhhacks]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Sherratt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing… Christina Last]]></title>
        <id>https://livingwithmachines.ac.uk/?p=1934</id>
        <link href="https://livingwithmachines.ac.uk/introducing-christina-last/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=introducing-christina-last"/>
        <updated>2021-07-29T12:32:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What is your name? Christina Last What is your background? I am a Research Data Scientist in the Research Engineering Group at the Turing, where I specialise in building machine learning solutions to understand our cities. My work bridges social data science, geographic machine learning, and machine learning operations. I enjoy working with city governments and international organizations on software and […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christina Last</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DHd tritt ADHO als konstituierende Organisation bei]]></title>
        <id>node/705</id>
        <link href="https://dig-hum.de/aktuelles/dhd-tritt-adho-als-konstituierende-organisation"/>
        <updated>2021-07-28T20:49:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wir freuen uns Ihnen mitzuteilen, dass der Verband Digital Humanities im deutschsprachigen Raum (DHd) der Alliance of Digital Humanities Organizations (ADHO) als konstituierende…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>406</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Conferencing from Home: ACH 2021 and !!Con]]></title>
        <id>841 at https://digitalhumanities.stanford.edu</id>
        <link href="https://digitalhumanities.stanford.edu/conferencing-home-ach-2021-and-con"/>
        <updated>2021-07-28T18:21:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 2019, I wrote a blog post about the experience of going to the DH conference in Utrecht, followed by the ACH conference in Pittsburgh. Two years later, it's time for another ACH write-up, with a very different point of comparison: !!Con, a tech conference celebrating "the joy, excitement, and surprise of computing". While I've attended and presented at other virtual events this year (including the CSDH-SCHN conference), as co-VP of ACH I was particularly committed to attending as much of that conference as I could, and volunteering as a chair, online respondent, and livetweeter. !!Con was a more serendipitous discovery thanks to a tweet from Scott Weingart. It was the first non-academic conference I've presented at, and while differences in both scale and nature make it hard to compare …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Quinn Dombrowski</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Call for Nominations and Applications: DHQ General Editor]]></title>
        <id>https://ach.org/?p=2233</id>
        <link href="https://ach.org/blog/2021/07/28/call-for-nominations-and-applications-dhq-general-editor/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-28T14:56:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Originally posted at Digital Humanities Quarterly (http://www.digitalhumanities.org/dhq/announcements/index.html) July 24, 2021 Digital Humanities Quarterly invites nominations and applications for a new General Editor to join the journal’s senior editorial team. This call is the first step in a longer process of updating DHQ’s editorial structure and practices, and the incoming editor will play a key role…Continue reading.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>paigecm</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ADHO begrüßt DHd als konstituierende Organisation/ADHO welcomes DHd as a Constituent Organization]]></title>
        <id>588792 at https://adho.org</id>
        <link href="https://adho.org/announcements/2021/adho-begr%C3%BC%C3%9Ft-dhd-als-konstituierende-organisationadho-welcomes-dhd-constituent"/>
        <updated>2021-07-28T11:57:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Die Alliance of Digital Humanities Organizations (ADHO) freut sich, dass der Verband Digital Humanities im deutschsprachigen Raum (DHd) als konstituierende Organisation beigetreten ist. Die gemeinsamen Ziele von ADHO und DHd haben eine lange Geschichte: Der DHd-Verband wurde am 7. Juli 2012 in Hamburg während der ADHO Digital Humanities Konferenz gegründet. Mit seinen mehr als 400 Mitgliedern und 12 Arbeitsgruppen, Stand  Januar 2021, möchte der DHd eine formale Interessengemeinschaft sein, die Forschung und Lehre im Bereich der Digital Humanities im deutschsprachigen Raum unterstützt. Der DHd-Verband unterstützt die Open Access Zeitschrift Zeitschrift für digitale Geisteswissenschaften (ZfdG), setzt sich für die Digital Humanities ein (z.B. gegenüber der Deutschen Forschungsgemeinschaft /…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>erdal.ayan@dhturkey.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Immers-Ed Global Hackathon]]></title>
        <id>1325 at https://eadh.org</id>
        <link href="https://eadh.org/news/2021/07/28/immers-ed-global-hackathon"/>
        <updated>2021-07-28T11:18:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[8 Aug 2021 - 00:00



Immers-Ed Global Hackathon



27 -30 September 2021
Apply by: 8 August 2021
Virtual
Announcing the first hackathon hosted by the University of Oxford dedicated to immersive technologies: Immers-Ed Global Hackathon. The event, modelled upon programming hackathons, brings together participants to creatively solve problems in the course of three days of intense collaboration.
The event tasks participants with devising solutions to challenges which were created or amplified by the pandemic in one of four key areas: Cultural Heritage, Medicine, Education and Environmental Sustainability.
Participants are invited to apply either individually or together with colleagues, as part of a team. No experience with hackathons or technical knowledge is required. The winning team will receive $10,000 in Amazon Web Services credit and professional mentoring and support to continue developing their idea.
For more information, including answers to commonly-asked questions, visit: https://oxr.eng.ox.ac.uk/hackox/
Apply here.
 
Organised by the University of Oxford's X-Reality Hub in collaboration with TORCH (En)coding Heritage Network and sponsored by Amazon Web Services. 
For questions, email v-hub@it.ox.ac.uk.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Communication Fellow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DHd-Twitter Account ist wieder erreichbar]]></title>
        <id>node/704</id>
        <link href="https://dig-hum.de/aktuelles/dhd-twitter-account-ist-wieder-erreichbar"/>
        <updated>2021-07-27T16:38:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Liebe DHd-Community,
der DHd-Twitter Account (@DHDInfo) funktioniert wieder.
Wir bitten die Ihnen ggf. entstandenen Umstände zu entschuldigen.
Beste Grüße,
Simone Kronenwett
---…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>406</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DHd-Twitter Account ist vorübergehend nicht erreichbar]]></title>
        <id>node/703</id>
        <link href="https://dig-hum.de/aktuelles/dhd-twitter-account-ist-vor%C3%BCbergehend-nicht-erreichbar"/>
        <updated>2021-07-27T16:37:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Liebe DHd-Community,
der DHd-Twitter Account (@DHDInfo) ist vorübergehend nicht erreichbar.
Wir melden uns wieder, sobald der Account wieder funktioniert.
Wir bitten die Umstände…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>406</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Long View Seminar – Reflecting on our First Year]]></title>
        <id>https://blogs.ucl.ac.uk/dh/?p=8188</id>
        <link href="https://blogs.ucl.ac.uk/dh/2021/07/27/long-view-seminar-reflecting-on-our-first-year/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-27T08:31:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a year dominated by a global pandemic and both remote working and teaching, we lost many of the traditional ways that we as scholars could stay connected. One of those, the traditional extra-curricular seminar series that was a coming together space for people at different stages of their career, had to go online. And […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>uczcrym</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[International workshop: Histories of Maintenance and Repair]]></title>
        <id>3533 at https://www.c2dh.uni.lu</id>
        <link href="https://www.c2dh.uni.lu/events/international-workshop-histories-maintenance-and-repair"/>
        <updated>2021-07-23T13:45:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the past fifteen years, maintenance and repair practices have gained increasing academic attention, but the literature in the fields of history and philosophy of technology, science and technology studies, sociology and anthropology of technology is still focused on invention and newness. Complementing recent calls for a history of technology-in-use (D. Edgerton), broken-world thinking (S. Jackson) and a history of technology “after innovation” (A. Russell & L. Vinsel), we are working on the first systematic historical investigation of repair and maintenance in a Western consumer society.
In the spirit of chasing this turn, we have invited international scholars to present their own take on the histories of maintenance and repair. These range from considering the philosophical implica…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stefan Krebs</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Event: Getting started with Linked Open Data]]></title>
        <id>https://scholarlytales.hcommons.org/?p=742</id>
        <link href="https://scholarlytales.hcommons.org/2021/07/23/event-getting-started-with-linked-open-data/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-23T09:56:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Nele Noppe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Job opportunity: Chief Archivist/Principal Information Scientist - Budapest]]></title>
        <id>1323 at https://eadh.org</id>
        <link href="https://eadh.org/news/2021/07/20/job-opportunity-chief-archivistprincipal-information-scientist-budapest"/>
        <updated>2021-07-20T09:53:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Job opportunity: Chief Archivist/Principal Information Scientist - Budapest



Position: Faculty
Location: Budapest
Status: Full time
Unit: Vera and Donald Blinken Open Society Archives
E-mail: advert050@ceuedu
Application deadline: Open until filled
Starting date: October 1, 2021
Website: https://www.ceu.edu/job/chief-archivistprincipal-information-scientist-0
The Vera and Donald Blinken Open Society Archives (OSA) at Central European University (CEU) based primarily in Budapest but with teaching tasks in Vienna, Austria invites applications for the Chief Archivist/Principal Information Scientist position. Blinken OSA (www.osaarchivum.org), one of the most important Cold War and human rights archives in the world, is looking for a highly talented, innovative, socially committed and techno…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Communication Fellow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[King’s College London – Digital: some are more equal than others]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rluk.ac.uk/?p=10306</id>
        <link href="https://www.rluk.ac.uk/kings-college-london-digital-some-are-more-equal-than-others/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-20T09:36:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alongside every other university in the UK, King’s College London moved almost all our activities online as the national lockdown began in March 2020. For Libraries & Collections this involved a massive acceleration in our shift to digital collections, online support, e-learning and home working. While much of this work was already under way [...]
The post King’s College London – Digital: some are more equal than others appeared first on Research Libraries UK.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christina Kamposiori</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Case Study: Scholarship and Collections. Manchester Digital Collections]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rluk.ac.uk/?p=10301</id>
        <link href="https://www.rluk.ac.uk/case-study-scholarship-and-collections-manchester-digital-collections/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-20T09:29:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Manchester Digital Collections (MDC) was launched in January 2020 with five sets of digitised materials from the world-class collections of the University of Manchester Library, Whitworth Gallery and Manchester Museum. We aimed to provide a platform of IIIF images and TEI metadata for researchers to share their work on collections and to encourage digital [...]
The post Case Study: Scholarship and Collections. Manchester Digital Collections appeared first on Research Libraries UK.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christina Kamposiori</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mit dem Hochschulverband Informationswissenschaft schließt sich ein weiterer Verband unserem WissZeitG Statement an]]></title>
        <id>node/702</id>
        <link href="https://dig-hum.de/aktuelles/dem-hochschulverband-informationswissenschaft-schlie%C3%9Ft-sich-ein-weiterer-verband-unserem"/>
        <updated>2021-07-16T15:34:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wir freuen uns, dass mit dem Hochschulverband Informationswissenschaft ein weiterer Fachverband unsere Stellungnahme zur Befristungspraxis an Hochschulen und außeruniversitären…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>406</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Neue DHd-Community auf Zenodo: DHd-Verbandsaktivitäten]]></title>
        <id>node/701</id>
        <link href="https://dig-hum.de/aktuelles/neue-dhd-community-zenodo-dhd-verbandsaktivit%C3%A4ten"/>
        <updated>2021-07-16T15:08:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bereits seit 2019 wird auf Zenodo eine DHd-Community betrieben und kuratiert (https://zenodo.org/communities/dhd/). Sie ist eine zentrale Sammelstelle für Materialien rund um die…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>406</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stellenangebot: Digital Humanist, Brahms-Gesamtausgabe Kiel]]></title>
        <id>node/700</id>
        <link href="https://dig-hum.de/aktuelles/stellenangebot-digital-humanist-brahms-gesamtausgabe-kiel"/>
        <updated>2021-07-14T17:57:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Das Akademievorhaben Brahms-Gesamtausgabe Kiel sucht zum 1. Oktober 2021 eine:n Wissenschaftliche:n Mitarbeiter:in / Digital Humanist (50%).
Bewerbungsfrist: 06.08.2021
Die…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>406</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[8 million Trove tags to explore!]]></title>
        <id>http://wragge.micro.blog/2021/07/14/million-trove-tags.html</id>
        <link href="https://updates.timsherratt.org/2021/07/14/million-trove-tags.html"/>
        <updated>2021-07-14T07:06:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve always been interested in the way people add value to resources in Trove. OCR correction tends to get all the attention, but Trove users have also been busy organising resources using tags, lists, and comments. I used to refer to tagging quite often in presentations, pointing to the different ways they were used. For example, ‘TBD’ is a workflow marker, used by text correctors to label articles that are ‘To Be Done’. My favourite was ‘LRRSA’, one of the most heavily-used tags across the whole of Trove. What does it mean? It stands for the Light Rail Research Society of Australia, and the tag is used by members to mark items of shared interest. It’s a great example of how something as simple as plain text tags can be used to support collaboration and build communities.

Until its updat…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Sherratt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creative AI: Models of Artistic Practice]]></title>
        <id>https://blogs.kcl.ac.uk/ddh/?p=3070</id>
        <link href="https://blogs.kcl.ac.uk/ddh/2021/07/12/creative-ai-models-of-artistic-practice/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-12T08:16:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do artists use the backend of machine learning in their artworks? How is Machine Learning transforming the making of meaning? These were the questions brought about in the Creative AI Lab’s presentation during the National College of Art and Design, Dublin (NCAD) Digital Culture Webinar Series hosted by Elaine Hoey (New Media Artist) and … 
Continue reading "Creative AI: Models of Artistic Practice"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shuprima Guha</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Editors' Note: July 2021]]></title>
        <id>e0d3c166-7d96-4a1a-8c39-f3ebec3bc96f</id>
        <link href="https://reviewsindh.pubpub.org/pub/ed-note-july-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-07-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Editors' note on the July 2021 issue of Reviews in Digital Humanities]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Roopika Risam</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Digital Community Engagement]]></title>
        <id>0e7ce1cb-739a-4c72-a419-712610b25df6</id>
        <link href="https://reviewsindh.pubpub.org/pub/digital-community-engagement"/>
        <updated>2021-07-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A review of Digital Community Engagement, an open-access volume of case studies on digital partnerships, edited by Rebecca S. Wingo, Jason A. Heppler, and Paul Schadewald]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Megan Smeznik</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Shakespeare and Company Project]]></title>
        <id>7701ea1a-cf89-49f6-acb2-8798e727bb3c</id>
        <link href="https://reviewsindh.pubpub.org/pub/shakespeare-and-company-project"/>
        <updated>2021-07-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A review of the Shakespeare and Company Project, a database of records from Sylvia Beach's Shakespeare and Company bookshop, created by Joshua Kotin]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrew Thacker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Project TwitLit]]></title>
        <id>818889bc-b43b-4eb0-95c4-d6d6668c8049</id>
        <link href="https://reviewsindh.pubpub.org/pub/project-twitter-literature"/>
        <updated>2021-07-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A review of Project TwitLit, a social media analysis project examining writing communities on Twitter, created by Christian Howard-Sukhil]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christina Boyles</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: War Stories]]></title>
        <id>c8d9ceb5-ed3d-4031-973b-44c944e01603</id>
        <link href="https://reviewsindh.pubpub.org/pub/war-stories"/>
        <updated>2021-07-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A review of War Stories, a digital project that tells the stories of children during World War II, created by Gabrielle Atwood Halko]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R.C. Miessler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Humanities-Centred AI (CHAI) : Call for Papers (Verlängerung bis 30.07.21)]]></title>
        <id>node/699</id>
        <link href="https://dig-hum.de/aktuelles/humanities-centred-ai-chai-call-for-papers-verl%C3%A4ngerung-300721"/>
        <updated>2021-07-11T15:56:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[44th German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2021)
Der Call for Papers ist eröffnet und die Deadline für die Einreichung von Beiträgen wurde bis zum 30.07.2021 verlängert…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>406</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rahtz Prize – Call for Nominations and Submissions 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://tei-c.org/?p=31163</id>
        <link href="https://tei-c.org/2021/07/09/rahtz-prize-call-for-nominations-and-submissions-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T18:57:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The TEI Consortium created the Rahtz Prize for TEI Ingenuity in memory of Sebastian Rahtz, who contributed significantly to the TEI infrastructure. The award is intended to honour Sebastian’s noteworthy technical and philosophical contributions to the TEI, and to encourage innovation in the TEI community. The Rahtz Prize for TEI Ingenuity is awarded to an […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martina Scholger</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DLCL ATS round-up, spring 2021]]></title>
        <id>836 at https://digitalhumanities.stanford.edu</id>
        <link href="https://digitalhumanities.stanford.edu/dlcl-ats-round-spring-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T17:51:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spring quarter gave me the first chance in a long while to take some time off. The first week of the quarter was my kids' spring break, which we spent in a cabin in the woods near Mt. Lassen with just the right amount of internet: enough to quietly keep an eye on email, not enough for Zoom. We've taken some other long weekends, and there's been periods when school has been closed for one or more kids. Nonetheless, here's where things stand at the end of spring quarter.
Existing projects
I've been continuing to refine the static, Jekyll-based site for the Global Medieval Sourcebook, with a few CSS tweaks left to do. I had the opportunity to present what we've done so far with Mae Velloso-Lyons (and Elizabeth Honig, the faculty member behind a Jan Brueghel Catalogue Raisonné I worked on at U…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Quinn Dombrowski</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[nnanno: a tool to help work with Newspaper Navigator images]]></title>
        <id>https://livingwithmachines.ac.uk/?p=1916</id>
        <link href="https://livingwithmachines.ac.uk/nnanno-a-tool-to-help-work-with-newspaper-navigator-images/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=nnanno-a-tool-to-help-work-with-newspaper-navigator-images"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T15:08:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Newspapers are a visual medium, communicating not only through text but also through visual information, including photographs, maps and other images. Research on historic newspapers, particularly with digital methods, has focused primarily on the text contained in the newspapers. However, there is potentially a lot to be learned by also looking at the visual content […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel van Strien</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Counts as Culture? Part I: Sentiment Analysis of The Times Music Reviews, 1950-2009 – train in the distance]]></title>
        <id>https://traininthedistance.wordpress.com/2021/05/07/what-counts-as-culture-part-i-sentiment-analysis-of-the-times-music-reviews-1950-2009/</id>
        <link href="https://openmethods.dariah.eu/2021/07/08/what-counts-as-culture-part-i-sentiment-analysis-of-the-times-music-reviews-1950-2009-train-in-the-distance/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-08T14:36:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction: This blog post by Lucy Havens presents a sentiment analysis of over 2000 Times Music Reviews using freely available tools: defoe for building the corpus of reviews, VADER for sentiment analysis and Jupiter Notebooks to provide a rich documentation and to connect the different components of the analysis. The description of the workflow comes with tool and method criticism reflections, including an outlook how to improve and continue to get better and more results.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucy Havens</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reminder: CfP DHd2022 endet am 15.07.2021]]></title>
        <id>node/698</id>
        <link href="https://dig-hum.de/aktuelles/reminder-cfp-dhd2022-endet-am-15072021"/>
        <updated>2021-07-08T10:10:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Die 8. Jahrestagung des Verbands »Digital Humanities im deutschsprachigen Raum e.V.« (DHd) findet vom 7. bis zum 11. März 2022 in Postdam statt.
Die DHd2022 hat das Thema »…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>406</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to new Lecturers at the Department of Digital Humanities 🎊]]></title>
        <id>https://blogs.kcl.ac.uk/ddh/?p=3080</id>
        <link href="https://blogs.kcl.ac.uk/ddh/2021/07/07/welcome-to-new-lecturers/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-07T15:14:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A very warm welcome to all of our new members of staff at the Department of Digital Humanities! Joining us ahead of the next academic year we have: Andrea Ballatore, Lecturer in Social and Cultural Informatics Barbara McGillivray, Lecturer in Digital Humanities and Cultural Computation Daniel Chavez Heras, Lecturer in Humanistic and Social Computing Education … 
Continue reading "Welcome to new Lecturers at the Department of Digital Humanities 🎊"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan Gray</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Neue DH-Projekte im DHd-Projekteschaufenster]]></title>
        <id>node/697</id>
        <link href="https://dig-hum.de/aktuelles/neue-dh-projekte-im-dhd-projekteschaufenster"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T15:25:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wir freuen uns, vier neue DH-Forschungsprojekte im DHd-Projekteschaufenster präsentieren zu dürfen:
Peter Handke Notizbücher. Digitale Edition
DARIAH-DE Repository
DARIAH-DE Geo-…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>406</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DH Student Intern – Courtney Priday]]></title>
        <id>https://digitalhumanities.exeter.ac.uk/?p=798</id>
        <link href="https://digitalhumanities.exeter.ac.uk/2021/07/dh-student-intern-courtney-priday/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T09:48:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hi, I’m Courtney and I’ve just completed my BA English degree. In my final year I have worked as an advisory intern in the DH Lab and loved every minute. In this very unusual year, I have been lucky enough to gain experience in the lab and have got to work on some very exciting […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gemma Poulton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stellenangebot: WMA für die Online-Plattform Digital Benin]]></title>
        <id>node/695</id>
        <link href="https://dig-hum.de/aktuelles/stellenangebot-wma-f%C3%BCr-die-online-plattform-digital-benin"/>
        <updated>2021-07-04T08:10:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Die Stiftung Museum am Rothenbaum sucht baldmöglichst für 12 Monate eine:n Wissenschaftliche:n Mitarbeiter:in für die Schaffung der Online-Plattform Digital Benin in Vollzeit.…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>406</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CfP: Virtual Summer School: Deep Learning for Language Analysis (30.8.-3.9.2021)]]></title>
        <id>node/694</id>
        <link href="https://dig-hum.de/aktuelles/cfp-virtual-summer-school-deep-learning-for-language-analysis-308-392021"/>
        <updated>2021-07-02T20:43:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Das Institut für Digital Humanities (IDH), das Cologne Center for eHumanities (CCeH) und das Data Center for the Humanities (DCH) richten mit Unterstützung der Competence Area III…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>406</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CFP TEI 2021: Next Gen TEI]]></title>
        <id>https://tei-c.org/?p=31131</id>
        <link href="https://tei-c.org/2021/07/02/cfp-tei-2021-next-gen-tei/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-02T14:33:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At DH 2017 in Montreal, the Text Encoding Initiative received the Antonio Zampolli Prize in recognition of our thirtieth anniversary. Four years and a pandemic later, the TEI Guidelines remain a significant part of the digital humanities toolkit, with a strong focus on internationalization, both linguistic and geographic. From Japan to Argentina, Austria to Cameroon, […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hugh Cayless</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DHA2021 Call For Proposals]]></title>
        <id>https://aa-dh.org/?p=414</id>
        <link href="https://aa-dh.org/2021/07/02/dha2021-call-for-proposals/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-02T03:23:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Australasian Association for Digital Humanities (aaDH) is pleased to invite proposals for DHA2021 (our COVID-delayed conference formerly known as DHA2020). DHA 2021 will take place from 22-25 November 2021. To allow for COVID-19 uncertainty, it will be a hybrid ‘In-person’ / ‘On-line’ conference held simultaneously in the city of Ōtautahi Christchurch, Aotearoa New Zealand, … Continue reading "DHA2021 Call For Proposals"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tully Barnett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mastering Latin Abbreviations and Hyphenations – The Bentham and DEEDS Projects]]></title>
        <id>https://readcoop.eu/?p=24907</id>
        <link href="https://readcoop.eu/mastering-latin-abbreviations-and-hyphenations-the-bentham-and-deeds-projects/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T12:40:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A collaboration between the Bentham Project of the University College London and the DEEDS (Documents of Early England Data Set) Project of the University of Toronto uses Transkribus for the transcription of an immense corpus of medieval charters from the 12th to the 15th century. The handwritten Latin of this period is very peculiar and […]
The post Mastering Latin Abbreviations and Hyphenations – The Bentham and DEEDS Projects appeared first on READ-COOP.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Florian Stauder</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Integrating GLAM Workbench news and discussion]]></title>
        <id>http://wragge.micro.blog/2021/07/01/integrating-glam-workbench.html</id>
        <link href="https://updates.timsherratt.org/2021/07/01/integrating-glam-workbench.html"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T05:18:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve spent a lot of time this year working on ways of improving the GLAM Workbench’s documentation and its integration with other services. Last year I created OzGLAM Help to provide a space where users of GLAM collections could ask questions and share discoveries – including a dedicated GLAM Workbench channel. Earlier this year, I tweaked my Micro.blog powered updates to include a dedicated GLAM Workbench news feed. Now I’ve brought the two together! What does this mean?
Any GLAM Workbench news that I post to my updates feed is now automatically added to OzGLAM Help
Links are automatically added to items in the news feed that let you add comments or questions in OzGLAM Help
So now there’s two-way communication between the services providing more ways for people to discover and discuss how the GLAM Workbench can help them.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Sherratt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GLAM Workbench now on YouTube!]]></title>
        <id>http://wragge.micro.blog/2021/07/01/glam-workbench-now.html</id>
        <link href="https://updates.timsherratt.org/2021/07/01/glam-workbench-now.html"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T04:51:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve started creating short videos to introduce or explain various components of the GLAM Workbench. The first video shows how you can visualise searches in Trove’s digitised newspapers using the latest version of QueryPic. It’s a useful introduction to the way access to collection data enables us to ask different types of questions of historical sources.


As with all GLAM Workbench resources, the video is openly-licensed – so feel free to stop it into your own course materials or workshops. It could, for example, provide an interesting little digital methods task in an Australian history unit.
I’ll be creating a second QueryPic video shortly, demonstrating how you can work with complex queries and differing timescales. Let me know if you find it useful, or if you have any ideas for future topics. #dhhacks]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Sherratt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UCLDH research activity June 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://blogs.ucl.ac.uk/dh/?p=8192</id>
        <link href="https://blogs.ucl.ac.uk/dh/2021/06/30/ucldh-research-june21/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-30T12:44:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The UCLDH team have been busy as ever, despite continuing COVID-19 restrictions. Here’s just a few examples of recent activity: Adam Crymble has published a monograph, Technology & the Historian: Transformations in the Digital Age (University of Illinois press, 2021) and a co-authored piece with Maria José Afanador-Llach (‘The Globally Unequal Promise of Digital Tools […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucy Stagg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zwangssoldaten, Malgré-Nous, Zwangsrekrutéiert? - Terms, Numbers and Statistics]]></title>
        <id>3510 at https://www.c2dh.uni.lu</id>
        <link href="https://www.c2dh.uni.lu/events/zwangssoldaten-malgre-nous-zwangsrekruteiert-terms-numbers-and-statistics"/>
        <updated>2021-06-30T09:52:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Zwangssoldaten, Malgré-Nous, Zwangsrekrutéiert – three regions, three terms, one fate? After the German invasion of its western neighbours, France, the Netherlands, Belgium and Luxembourg in 1940, the border regions reaching from Eastern Belgium over Luxembourg to Alsace-Lorraine were seen by the Third Reich as lost German territories that needed reintegration into the Reich. One part of that reintegration policy was recruiting the local female and male youth into German labour services and armed forces.
This workshop will present the recruitments in each of these areas and focus on their historical similarities and differences. Further,  it will analyse the etymology and the legal aspect of the different terms describing the recruits. The workshop’s emphasis is on the quantitative analysis of contemporary sources. How can certain sources for example help researchers to challenge persisting narratives and statistics, in order to give a clearer view of the numbers, the recruitment processes and the war experiences within Eastern Belgium, Alsace-Lorraine and Luxembourg?
 
Thursday, 14 October 2021
10.00 - 17.30
Hybrid event
Maison Sciences Humaines, 11 Portes des Sciences, 4365 Esch/Alzette
If you wish to particpate in-person, please contact us at warlux@uni.lu before 30 September 2021. Places are limited due to health regulations.
and
Online via Webex



Please register via Eventbrite to join the workshop online.
Languages: German, French and English
We will welcome speakers from Belgium, France, Germany and Luxembourg,
 
For more information on the WARLUX-project, please have a look on our website and research blog https://digiwarhist.hypotheses.org.
14 October 2021
  Contemporary history of Luxembourg
  WARLUX - Soldiers and their communities in WWII: The impact and legacy of war experiences in Luxembourg
  Border studies  WW2
  Conferences
  Published  
    Hide image in content detail]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Noëlle Schon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction to IIIF]]></title>
        <id>https://dh.rutgers.edu/?p=77332</id>
        <link href="https://dh.rutgers.edu/introduction-to-iiif/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=introduction-to-iiif"/>
        <updated>2021-06-29T21:03:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By Ben Bakelaar and Caterina Agostini   IIIF is an acronym that stands for International Image Interoperability Format. An easy way to think of IIIF is like a webpage. A webpage is built with HTML, via hypertext markup language. It pulls together text, images, and other multimedia into a single view. In the same way, a IIIF object is built using JSON, and links together metadata and powerful image capabilities which allow institutions to deliver ultra-high resolution images quickly and efficiently to a IIIF viewer. Any image (and even audio and video) can become a IIIF object by building a manifest that uses the IIIF standard to describe its]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caterina Agostini</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Visualizando libros difundidos y censurados durante la Guerra Fría: 1956-1971. El caso Alfred Reisch]]></title>
        <id>http://revistas.uned.es/index.php/RHD/article/view/27247</id>
        <link href="https://openmethods.dariah.eu/2021/06/28/visualizando-libros-difundidos-y-censurados-durante-la-guerra-fria-1956-1971-el-caso-alfred-reisch/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T11:39:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction: This article explores the potential use of data-driven methods to visualise and interpret the impact of Western efforts to influence Cold War dynamics using a covert book distribution programme. Based on a documentary corpus connected to the 2013 book by Alfred Reisch, which documented efforts by the CIA to disseminate books in the Soviet Bloc in the period 1956-1971, the authors use the Tableau Public platform to re-assess information science methods for researching historical events. Their analysis suggests that books distributed did not tend to have a more obvious political slant, but were more likely to have a broader universalist outlook. While it skirts around some of the limitations of visualization (highlighted elsewhere by Drucker and others) it offers a solid introduction to the benefits of a data-driven approach to a general audience.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Author on Source</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stellungnahme des DHd-Verbands zur Befristungspraxis an Hochschulen und außeruniversitären Forschungseinrichtungen in Deutschland]]></title>
        <id>node/693</id>
        <link href="https://dig-hum.de/aktuelles/stellungnahme-des-dhd-verbands-zur-befristungspraxis-hochschulen-und-au%C3%9Feruniversit%C3%A4ren"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T08:23:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Der Vorstand des DHd-Verbands, dem Wissenschaftler:innen auf befristeten ebenso wie auf unbefristeten Stellen angehören, möchte mit der vorliegenden Stellungnahme Position in der…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>406</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GLAM Workbench office hours]]></title>
        <id>http://wragge.micro.blog/2021/06/28/glam-workbench-office.html</id>
        <link href="https://updates.timsherratt.org/2021/06/28/glam-workbench-office.html"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T04:04:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To help you make use of the GLAM Workbench, I’ve set up an ‘office hours’ time slot every Friday when people can book in for 30 minute chats via Zoom. Want to talk about how you might use the GLAM Workbench in your latest research project? Are you having trouble getting started with GLAM data? Or perhaps you have some ideas for future notebooks you’d like to share? Just click on the ‘Book a chat’ link in the GLAM Workbench, or head straight to the scheduling page to set up a time!

This is yet another experiment to see how I can support the use of GLAM data and the development of digital skills with the GLAM Workbench. Let me know if you think it’s worthwhile. #dhhacks]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Sherratt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Missing Links’ – new open access article!]]></title>
        <id>http://wragge.micro.blog/2021/06/28/missing-links-new.html</id>
        <link href="https://updates.timsherratt.org/2021/06/28/missing-links-new.html"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T03:08:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An article written by Kate Bagnall and me has just been published in a special issue of the Journal of World History focusing on digital history. And it’s open access!
The article is ‘Missing Links: Data Stories from the Archive of British Settler Colonial Citizenship’. In it we document our efforts to assemble a number of different datasets relating to naturalization. Here’s the abstract:
Digitized sources and digital methods are changing the way that we do history. For historians of the British Empire, the digital age offers new possibilities for investigating the lives of those who moved around the empire and across the world. However, much discussion of the possibilities and problems of digital history have focused on the creation and use of full text resources, skipping over the analytical opportunities offered by the descriptive systems in which those texts are embedded. This article is an attempt to fill this gap by documenting a journey through archival data relating to nineteenth-century Chinese naturalization in the Pacific Rim settler colonies of Australia, New Zealand, and Canada. We argue that such data stories are critical if we are to understand both possibilities and pitfalls of research in digital collections.
There’s also an GitHub repository with code and data related to the article.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Sherratt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ihre User-Experience ist gefragt! (remote)]]></title>
        <id>node/691</id>
        <link href="https://dig-hum.de/aktuelles/ihre-user-experience-ist-gefragt-remote"/>
        <updated>2021-06-27T19:08:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Im Rahmen eines User-Experience-Tests wird ein Service im Bereich digitaler Forschungsinfrastrukturen untersucht. Hierfür suchen wir Sie als Proband*innen mit und ohne…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>406</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[»DHd2022: Kulturen des digitalen Gedächtnisses« (Potsdam, März 2022). Endspurt: Noch 2,5 Wochen bis zur Deadline!]]></title>
        <id>node/690</id>
        <link href="https://dig-hum.de/aktuelles/%C2%BBdhd2022-kulturen-des-digitalen-ged%C3%A4chtnisses%C2%AB-potsdam-m%C3%A4rz-2022-endspurt-noch-25-wochen"/>
        <updated>2021-06-27T19:05:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In zweieinhalb Wochen, am 15. Juli, endet der Call for Papers der DHd2022: »Kulturen des digitalen Gedächtnisses« (hier ist der Call zu finden: https://www.dhd2022.de/cfp/).
Die 8…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>406</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Neue Perspektiven auf die Geschichte des Bergbaus an der Saar (Werkstattbericht)]]></title>
        <id>3501 at https://www.c2dh.uni.lu</id>
        <link href="https://www.c2dh.uni.lu/events/neue-perspektiven-auf-die-geschichte-des-bergbaus-der-saar-werkstattbericht"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T11:38:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The REMIX lecture series accompanies the C²DH based research project “Remixing Industrial Pasts in the Digital Age”. The project explores the history of cultures, populations and territories of the Minett region and will be a sustainable contribution to the “European Capital of Culture Esch 2022” programme. The project is funded by Esch2022 ASBL.
Since the REMIX/Esch2022 project thematically includes the neighbouring regions in a comparative and transregional perspective, this lecture is dedicated to the mining history of the Saar region.
On 6 July, Birgit Metzger will give a lecture on Neue Perspektiven auf die Geschichte des Bergbaus an der Saar (Werkstattbericht) [New perspectives on the history of mining in the Saar (workshop report)]. As a social figure, the miner is deeply anchored i…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Noëlle Schon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA['The Romanticism of Hell'. Environmental History of the Saar-region in the 19th-century]]></title>
        <id>3500 at https://www.c2dh.uni.lu</id>
        <link href="https://www.c2dh.uni.lu/events/romanticism-hell-environmental-history-saar-region-19th-century"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T11:24:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The REMIX lecture series accompanies the C²DH based research project “Remixing Industrial Pasts in the Digital Age”. The project explores the history of cultures, populations and territories of the Minett region and will be a sustainable contribution to the “European Capital of Culture Esch 2022” programme. The project is funded by Esch2022 ASBL.
Since the REMIX/Esch2022 project thematically includes the neighbouring regions in a comparative and transregional perspective, this lecture is dedicated to the environmental history of the Saar region.
On 29 June,  Markus Lay will present “The Romanticism of Hell”. Environmental History of the Saar-region in the 19th-century. In Imperial Germany, the industrial region along the Saar-River was the third most important of its kind. Surprisingly, there are not many papers to be found about its environmental history, despite an abundance of source material. The lecture will focus on the relatively new field of environmental justice and present case studies of environmental conflicts.
Markus Lay is office manager of Saarland’s historical commission and was fellow of the Hans-Blöcker-Foundation. His dissertational work focuses on the environmental history of the region during industrialisation. The “work-in-progress” is planned to be presented on umweltgeschichte.net as a Digital Public History project. In his Masters thesis he concentrated on Apiarian Societies and the spreading of apicultural innovations during the 18th and 19th century in Europe.
 
Tuesday, 29 June 2021
17.00 - 18.30 on Webex
To receive the link to this online event, please send an e-mail to Werner Tschacher (werner.tschacher@uni.lu).
29 June 2021
  Public history
  Remixing Industrial Pasts in the Digital Age: Sounds, Images, Ecologies, Practices and Materialities in Space and Time
  Industrial history  Regional history
  Conferences
  Published  
    Hide image in content detail]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Noëlle Schon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Call for Nominations to EADH Executive Committee]]></title>
        <id>1319 at https://eadh.org</id>
        <link href="https://eadh.org/news/2021/06/22/call-nominations-eadh-executive-committee"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T17:32:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[21 Jul 2021 - 00:00



Call for Nominations to EADH Executive Committee



Dear EADH members, 
The European Association for Digital Humanities (EADH) seeks to elect two (2) new board members for its Executive Committee for the term 2021-2024 and now opens its Call for Nominations. 
EADH highlights the importance of a diverse and representative Executive Committee, and welcomes candidates from all backgrounds. For further information, please see our diversity and inclusivity statement <https://eadh.org/about/diversity-and-inclusivity>. 
For each person wishing to be nominated for election, the EADH Elections Committee must receive the following three documents:
a) two nomination statements by EADH members (here, the proposers), stating the name of the person they wish to nominate (that is, …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Communication Fellow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenMethods Spotlights #3 Keeping a smart diary of research processes with NeMO and the Scholarly Ontology]]></title>
        <id>http://openmethods.dariah.eu/?p=3052</id>
        <link href="https://openmethods.dariah.eu/2021/06/22/openmethods-spotlights-3-keeping-a-smart-diary-of-research-processes-with-nemo-and-the-scholarly-ontology/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T14:13:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the next episode, we are looking behind the scenes of two ontologies: NeMO and the Scholarly Ontology (SO) with Panos Constantopoulos and Vayianos Pertsas who tell us the story behind these ontologies and explain how they can be used to ease or upcycle your daily works as a researcher. We discuss the value of knowledge graphs, how NeMO and SO connect with the emerging DH ontology landscape and beyond, why Open Access is a precondition of populating them, the Greek DH landscape …and many more!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Erzsebet Tóth-Czifra</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Special Interest Group on IIIF]]></title>
        <id>https://dh.rutgers.edu/?p=77319</id>
        <link href="https://dh.rutgers.edu/special-interest-group-on-iiif/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=special-interest-group-on-iiif"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T22:04:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By Caterina Agostini and Ben Bakelaar   Digital images and tools are attracting the interest of scholars in the humanities. In particular, the International Image Interoperability Framework (IIIF) allows for high quality images and supports a variety of uses and applications including deep zoom, comparison, annotation, and transcription of digital images. With the current pandemic limiting travel and access to libraries and museums, in the Spring 2021 we founded a new DH Special Interest Group at Rutgers focused on IIIF. In the first meeting, we shared our work and research interests and connected with members of the Rutgers community, from Rutgers University Libraries, the Office]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caterina Agostini</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DH Student Intern – Laura Jones]]></title>
        <id>https://digitalhumanities.exeter.ac.uk/?p=781</id>
        <link href="https://digitalhumanities.exeter.ac.uk/2021/06/dh-student-intern-laura-jones/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T13:28:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hi, I’m Laura, a third year History and Archaeology student and this will be my second year at the Digital Humanities Lab as an intern. My interests span 2D digitisation to 3D digitisation techniques such as RTI (Reflectance Transformation Imaging) and photogrammetry. I love how these techniques are applied to cultural heritage and wider research […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gemma Poulton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Community Open Principles: Before, During and After the Global Pandemic]]></title>
        <id>1318 at https://eadh.org</id>
        <link href="https://eadh.org/news/2021/06/21/community-open-principles-during-and-after-global-pandemic-0"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T09:15:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Community Open Principles: Before, During and After the Global Pandemic



The Force11 Working Group Reimagining Educational Practices for Open (REPO) will be hosting its second webinar on Jun 30, 2021 at 13:00 UTC.
Community Open Principles: Before, During and After the Global Pandemic
Dr. Ana Persic, UNESCO,
Dr. Arianna Becerril García, AmeliCA,
Dr. Johanna Havemann, Open Science MOOC,
Osman Aldirdiri, AfricArXiv
When we talk about Open (Open Science, Open Data, Open Access) what do we mean? How can we navigate the different definitions of what it means to be a community and to be Open? How do we engage with communities and train members around Open? What evidence are we using of how we are addressing Open? How can we be more inclusive and align our Open principles to foster norms, incentives, and recognition? Have our understandings around Open shifted during the pandemic? 
This online webinar will address these questions via the experiences of invited open science communities, how they have designed and applied their open (science) principles before and during the pandemic, particularly with regard to outreach and training, while also looking out at the horizon, at a future beyond the pandemic. The webinar aims to include open (science) perspectives from a diverse group of communities, learn from their approaches, how they have evolved, and identify possible next steps that all, in our global community can consider.
Register now]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Communication Fellow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Community Open Principles: Before, During and After the Global Pandemic]]></title>
        <id>1317 at https://eadh.org</id>
        <link href="https://eadh.org/news/2021/06/21/community-open-principles-during-and-after-global-pandemic"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T09:14:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Community Open Principles: Before, During and After the Global Pandemic



The Force11 Working Group Reimagining Educational Practices for Open (REPO) will be hosting its second webinar on Jun 30, 2021 at 13:00 UTC.
Community Open Principles: Before, During and After the Global Pandemic
Dr. Ana Persic, UNESCO,
Dr. Arianna Becerril García, AmeliCA,
Dr. Johanna Havemann, Open Science MOOC,
Osman Aldirdiri, AfricArXiv
When we talk about Open (Open Science, Open Data, Open Access) what do we mean? How can we navigate the different definitions of what it means to be a community and to be Open? How do we engage with communities and train members around Open? What evidence are we using of how we are addressing Open? How can we be more inclusive and align our Open principles to foster norms, incentives, and recognition? Have our understandings around Open shifted during the pandemic? 
This online webinar will address these questions via the experiences of invited open science communities, how they have designed and applied their open (science) principles before and during the pandemic, particularly with regard to outreach and training, while also looking out at the horizon, at a future beyond the pandemic. The webinar aims to include open (science) perspectives from a diverse group of communities, learn from their approaches, how they have evolved, and identify possible next steps that all, in our global community can consider.
Register now]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Communication Fellow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Visiting Professor David Berry on Explainability and Interpretability as Critical Infrastructure Practice]]></title>
        <id>https://blogs.kcl.ac.uk/ddh/?p=3063</id>
        <link href="https://blogs.kcl.ac.uk/ddh/2021/06/21/david-berry-on-explainability/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T08:20:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[David Berry is currently visiting the Department of Digital Humanities as Visiting Professor of Critical Theory and Digital Humanities. The following post from David introduces some of his current research on explainability and interpretability. He is giving a talk about this work at the Infrastructural Interventions workshop on Tuesday 22nd June. I am very excited … 
Continue reading "Visiting Professor David Berry on Explainability and Interpretability as Critical Infrastructure Practice"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan Gray</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[QueryPic: The Next Generation]]></title>
        <id>http://wragge.micro.blog/2021/06/21/querypic-the-next.html</id>
        <link href="https://updates.timsherratt.org/2021/06/21/querypic-the-next.html"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T00:50:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[QueryPic is a tool to visualise searches in Trove’s digitised newspapers. I created the first version way back in 2011, and since then it’s taken a number of different forms. The latest version introduces some new features:
Automatic query creation – construct your search in the Trove web interface, then just copy and paste the url into QueryPic. This means you can take advantage of Trove’s advanced search and facets to build complex queries.
Multiple time scales – previous versions only aggregated search results by year, but now you can also aggregate by month, or by day. QueryPic will automatically choose a time unit based on the date range of your query, but if you’re not happy with the result you can change it!
Links back to Trove – click on any of the points on the chart to search Trove within that time period. This enables you to zoom in and out of your results, from the high-level visualisation, to individual articles.

This version of QueryPic is built within a Jupyter notebook, and designed to run using Voila (which hides all the code and makes the notebook look like a web app). See the Trove Newspapers section of the GLAM Workbench for more information. If you’d like to give it a try, just click the button below to run it live using Binder.

Hope you find it useful! #dhhacks]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Sherratt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everyone gets a Lab!]]></title>
        <id>http://wragge.micro.blog/2021/06/21/everyone-gets-a.html</id>
        <link href="https://updates.timsherratt.org/2021/06/21/everyone-gets-a.html"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T00:00:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I recently took part in a panel at the IIPC Web Archiving Conference discussing ‘Research use of web archives: a Labs approach’. My fellow panellists described some amazing stuff going on in European cultural heritage organisations to support researchers who want to make use of web archives. My ‘lab’ doesn’t have a physical presence, or an institutional home, but it does provide a starting point for researchers, and with the latest Reclaim Cloud and Docker integrations, everyone can have their own web archives lab! Here’s my 8 minute video. The slides are available here.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Sherratt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stellenangebot: WMA im Projekt Burchards Dekret Digital (Mainz, 50%, EG 13 TV-L)]]></title>
        <id>node/689</id>
        <link href="https://dig-hum.de/aktuelles/stellenangebot-wma-im-projekt-burchards-dekret-digital-mainz-50-eg-13-tv-l"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T17:58:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Die Johannes Gutenberg-Universität Mainz (JGU) gehört zu den großen Universitäten in Deutschland. In der Wissenschaftsregion Rhein-Main entfaltet sie ihre Leistungsstärke,…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>406</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome 2021 Communications Fellows]]></title>
        <id>588779 at https://adho.org</id>
        <link href="https://adho.org/announcements/2021/welcome-2021-communications-fellows"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T16:28:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are thrilled to welcome Erdal Ayan and Anna Sofia Lippolis as ADHO's 2021 Communications Fellows:
Erdal Ayan is currently a PhD candidate in the department of English and American Studies at University of Kassel and a part-time master student in the Web Science Master Program at TH-Koeln. He is holding two bachelors (English Language and Literature and Sociology) and two masters degrees (English Language Teaching (ELT) & Computer Education and Instructional Technologies). He has got a broad research interest and/but his main focus is on data/text mining, sentiment analysis (opinion mining), topic modeling, network analysis (community detection), web development. He worked as teacher and lecturer for English before moving to Germany in 2017. He completed his voluntary internship in the C…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>drupaladmin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New ERC Project Exploring the Intersection between Surveillance and Morality]]></title>
        <id>https://blogs.kcl.ac.uk/ddh/?p=3061</id>
        <link href="https://blogs.kcl.ac.uk/ddh/2021/06/17/new-erc-project-exploring-the-intersection-between-surveillance-and-morality/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T08:37:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘Smart cities’, ‘employee assistance programmes’, the pervasive language of ‘security’ – the implementation of surveillance technologies has consistently been framed in relation to moral ideas. This ambiguity has been observed by surveillance scholars for many years, David Lyon once describing the alternating ends of ‘care’ and ‘control’ which these technologies serve. Yet the study of … 
Continue reading "New ERC Project Exploring the Intersection between Surveillance and Morality"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vita Peacock</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Report on ACH Racial Justice Project]]></title>
        <id>https://ach.org/?p=2213</id>
        <link href="https://ach.org/blog/2021/06/16/report-on-ach-racial-justice-project/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T18:07:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As a key step toward meeting the goals described in our Statement on Black LIves Matter, Structural Racism, and Our Organization, the officers and members of the ACH Executive Council have worked during the first half of 2021 with consultants from DeEtta Jones and Associates on a review of the organization’s policies, procedures, and governance…Continue reading.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kathleen Fitzpatrick</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Luxembourg: from steel to the knowledge economy and beyond]]></title>
        <id>3472 at https://www.c2dh.uni.lu</id>
        <link href="https://www.c2dh.uni.lu/events/luxembourg-steel-knowledge-economy-and-beyond"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T11:13:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To reflect on the history of the Luxembourg economy and sketch out future scenarios, the Europe Direct Information Centre (EDIC) at the University of Luxembourg and its partners, the Luxembourg Institute of Socio-Economic Research (LISER) and the Luxembourg national innovation agency Luxinnovation, are pleased to invite you to the online webinar “Luxembourg: from steel to the knowledge economy and beyond”.
Despite its small size in terms of geography (2,586km2) and population (626,100 people on 1 January 2020), Luxembourg has an open, dynamic, innovative economy that is one of the most successful at international level – in 2019 its GDP per capita was 261% the European average and its growth rate was the third highest of the EU’s then 28 Member States – and also one of the least affected b…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Noëlle Schon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA["Humanitarian Mapping and Spatial Analysis" by Rupert Allan]]></title>
        <id>33438 at http://digihum.ut.ee</id>
        <link href="http://digihum.ut.ee/event/humanitarian-mapping-and-spatial-analysis-rupert-allan"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T14:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Asukoht: 

Zoom



...
 Loe lähemalt "Humanitarian Mapping and Spatial Analysis" by Rupert Allan kohta]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>a71389</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[#CfP LaTeCH-CLfL 2021]]></title>
        <id>1316 at https://eadh.org</id>
        <link href="https://eadh.org/news/2021/06/14/cfp-latech-clfl-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T13:55:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[5 Aug 2021 - 00:00



#CfP LaTeCH-CLfL 2021



The 5th Joint SIGHUM Workshop on Computational Linguistics for Cultural Heritage, Social Sciences, Humanities and Literature
to be held on-line on 11 November 2021 in conjunction with EMNLP 2021
https://sighum.wordpress.com/events/latech-clfl-2021/
Second Call for Papers (with apologies for cross-posting)
Organisers: Stefania Degaetano-Ortlieb, Anna Kazantseva, Nils Reiter, Stan Szpakowicz
LaTeCH-CLfL 2021 is the fifth in a series of meetings for NLP researchers who work with data from the broadly understood arts, humanities and social sciences, and for specialists in those disciplines who apply NLP techniques in their work. The workshop continues a long tradition of annual meetings. The SIGHUM Workshops on Language Technology for Cultural Her…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Communication Fellow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Representation of Borders in Industrial Films on the Saarland’s Heavy Industry (1931-2019)]]></title>
        <id>3470 at https://www.c2dh.uni.lu</id>
        <link href="https://www.c2dh.uni.lu/events/representation-borders-industrial-films-saarlands-heavy-industry-1931-2019"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T11:48:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Industrial films are a valuable resource for research in the field of cultural studies as they are both mediator and part of industrial culture. In the Saarland, as well as in the Greater Region as a whole, many industrial films were created throughout the last century. The industries treated include but are not limited to glass and porcelain manufacturing, brewing and viticulture as well as the iron, steel and coal industry. Looking at borders, this talk will focus on the heavy industries, in which geographical border crossings are rendered obligatory by ore and coal basins extending over national borders. However, geographical borders are only one of many types of borders which play an important role in the context of the heavy industry and are represented in respective industrial films.…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Noëlle Schon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Minor change to Reclaim Cloud config]]></title>
        <id>http://wragge.micro.blog/2021/06/14/minor-change-to.html</id>
        <link href="https://updates.timsherratt.org/2021/06/14/minor-change-to.html"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T04:44:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When the 1-click installer for Reclaim Cloud works its magic and turns GLAM Workbench repositories into your own, personal digital labs, it creates a new work directory mounted inside of your main Jupyter directory. This new directory is independent of the Docker image used to run Jupyter, so it’s a handy place to copy things if you ever want to update the Docker image. However, I just realised that there was a permissions problem with the work directory which meant you couldn’t write files to it from within Jupyter.
To fix the problem, I’ve added an extra line to the reclaim-manifest.jps config file to make the Jupyter user the owner of the work directory:
	- cmd[cp]: chown -R jovyan:jovyan /home/jovyan/work

This takes care of any new installations. If you have an existing installation, you can either just create a completely new environment using the updated config, or you can manually change the permissions:
Hover over the name of your environment in the control panel to display the option buttons.
Click on the Settings button. A new box will open at the bottom of the control panel with all the settings options.
Click on ‘SSH Access’ in the left hand menu of the settings box.
Click on the ‘SSH Connection’ tab.
Under ‘Web SSH’ click on the Connect button and select the default node.
A terminal session will open. At the command line enter the following:
	chown -R jovyan:jovyan /home/jovyan/work




Done! See the Using Reclaim Cloud section of the GLAM Workbench for more information.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Sherratt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Preprint! The limits and affordances of online collections]]></title>
        <id>http://wragge.micro.blog/2021/06/14/preprint-the-limits.html</id>
        <link href="https://updates.timsherratt.org/2021/06/14/preprint-the-limits.html"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T03:13:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been working on an essay for publication in a forthcoming edited collection. I wanted to explore how the practice of history in Australia had been changed by GLAM organisations making their collections available online – both the new possibilities that had emerged, and the problems that remained. In the end I focused on three areas – discovery, digitisation, and research infrastructure. If you’re interested, I’ve shared a preprint on Zenodo.
Here’s a taste:
Just twenty years ago, historical research often entailed long hours spent at a microfilm reader, browsing newspaper after newspaper in the hope of finding something relevant. The changes wrought by Trove, and other digital collections, seem revolutionary, but as with all revolutions there have been gains and losses. Alongside the wonders wrought by digitisation, this chapter has tried to highlight some of the paths not taken. The online resources we now use daily are not simply the products of technology – priorities have been set, funding has been distributed, decisions made about what to include and what to leave out. Cultural heritage collections are not just put online, they are placed within specific contexts of discovery and use. Each object, each version, each interface comes with a set of limitations and affordances that together determine what is possible. We do not know yet how these decisions will shape the sorts of histories that we write.
I enjoyed reminding myself about some early digital initiatives in the GLAM sector, but as is usual with these sorts of projects, I had to leave a lot out. It’s made me think about developing a larger project documenting our gains and losses.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Sherratt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trove Query Parser]]></title>
        <id>http://wragge.micro.blog/2021/06/14/trove-query-parser.html</id>
        <link href="https://updates.timsherratt.org/2021/06/14/trove-query-parser.html"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T02:46:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here’s a new little Python package that you might find useful. It simply takes a search url from Trove’s Newspapers & Gazettes category and converts it into a set of parameters that you can use to request data from the Trove API. While some parameters are used both in the web interface and the API, there are a lot of variations – this package means you don’t have to keep track of all the differences!
It’s very simple to use.

The code for the parser has been basically lifted from the Trove Newspaper Harvester. I wanted to separate it out so that I could use it at various spots in the GLAM Workbench and in other projects.
This package, the documentation, and the tests were all created using nbdev, which is really quite a fun way to develop Python packages. #dhhacks]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Sherratt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: RSHHGG Lab]]></title>
        <id>48e9feee-077d-4ef5-a4dc-82b26141e7dd</id>
        <link href="https://reviewsindh.pubpub.org/pub/rshhgg-lab"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A review of  RSHHGG Lab, an index for Revue de la société Haïtienne d’histoire, de géographie et de géologie (RSHHGG), directed by Chelsea Stieber]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hadassah St. Hubert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Editors' Note: June 2021]]></title>
        <id>75d38955-4050-487a-893c-bafb816996fc</id>
        <link href="https://reviewsindh.pubpub.org/pub/ed-note-june-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Editors' note on the June 2021 issue of Reviews in Digital Humanities]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Roopika Risam</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: GeoMAP]]></title>
        <id>0871ddbf-23b0-4ffd-b2cf-04ebf2e2c0b6</id>
        <link href="https://reviewsindh.pubpub.org/pub/geomap"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A review of GeoMAP, a cartographic project on the history of the Parisian art market, created by Léa Saint-Raymond, Félicie Faizand de Maupeou, and Julien Cavero]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristan M. Hanson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Emblem/as]]></title>
        <id>603a6acc-d92e-4d3b-8ad2-ca8a056566c0</id>
        <link href="https://reviewsindh.pubpub.org/pub/emblemas"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A review of Emblem/as, a  work of electronic literature exploring personal and geographic cartography, created by Tina Escaja]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Saum-Pascual</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Against All Odds]]></title>
        <id>aec6c6f0-dc8c-48a9-a8bf-533815a76313</id>
        <link href="https://reviewsindh.pubpub.org/pub/against-all-odds"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A review of Against All Odds, a digital archive of the African American men who served in the Mississippi state legislature from Reconstruction until the 1890s, created by DeeDee Baldwin]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kimber Thomas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some GLAM Workbench stats]]></title>
        <id>http://wragge.micro.blog/2021/06/13/some-glam-workbench.html</id>
        <link href="https://updates.timsherratt.org/2021/06/13/some-glam-workbench.html"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T08:01:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I deliberately don’t keep any stats about GLAM Workbench visits, because I think they’re pretty meaningless. On the other hand, I’m always interested to see how often GLAM Workbench repositories are launched on Binder. Rather than just random clicks, these numbers represent the number of times users started new computing sessions using the GLAM Workbench. I just compiled these stats for the past year, and I was very pleased to see that the Web Archives section has been launched over 1,000 times in the past twelve months! The Trove Newspapers and Trove Newspaper Harvester repositories are also well used – on average these are both being launched more than once a day.

The GLAM Workbench is never going to attract massive numbers of users – it’s all about being there when a researcher needs help to use GLAM collections. One or two launches per day means one or two researchers from somewhere around the world are able to explore new datasets, or ask new questions. I think that’s pretty important.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Sherratt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More Reclaim Cloud integrations!]]></title>
        <id>http://wragge.micro.blog/2021/06/13/more-reclaim-cloud.html</id>
        <link href="https://updates.timsherratt.org/2021/06/13/more-reclaim-cloud.html"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T07:28:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Five of the GLAM Workbench repositories now have automatically built Docker images and 1-click integration with Reclaim Cloud – ANU Archives, Trove Newspapers, Trove Newspaper Harvester, NAA RecordSearch, & Web Archives.

This means you can launch your very own version of these GLAM Workbench repositories in the cloud, where all your downloads and experiments will be saved! Find out more on the Using Reclaim Cloud page.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Sherratt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get your GLAM datasets here!]]></title>
        <id>http://wragge.micro.blog/2021/06/13/get-your-glam.html</id>
        <link href="https://updates.timsherratt.org/2021/06/13/get-your-glam.html"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T07:12:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve updated my harvest of Australian GLAM datasets from state/national government open data portals. There’s now 387 datasets, containing 1049 files (including 684 CSVs). There’s a list if you want to browse, and a CSV file if you want to download all the metadata. For more more information see the data portals section of the GLAM Workbench.

If you’re interested in finding out what’s inside all those 684 CVS files, take the GLAM CSV Explorer for a spin! It’s also been given a refresh, with new data and a new interface. #dhhacks]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Sherratt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day of Digital Humanities 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://blogs.kcl.ac.uk/ddh/?p=3055</id>
        <link href="https://blogs.kcl.ac.uk/ddh/2021/06/10/day-of-digital-humanities-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T15:46:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a collection of blog posts members of the department contributed to the annual Day of Digital Humanities, a global online event which was this year themed on ‘multilingual digital humanities’. These were originally published on the Language Acts & Worldmaking website at https://languageacts.org/blog/day-of-digital-humanities-part-1/ and https://languageacts.org/blog/day-of-digital-humanities-part-2/ Introduction by Paul Spence This year’s Day of … 
Continue reading "Day of Digital Humanities 2021"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Spence</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What could be the digital humanities’ Hugging Face?]]></title>
        <id>https://livingwithmachines.ac.uk/?p=1904</id>
        <link href="https://livingwithmachines.ac.uk/what-could-be-the-digital-humanities-hugging-face/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=what-could-be-the-digital-humanities-hugging-face"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T07:36:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[🤗 Giovanni Colavizza and Kaspar Beelen asked digital humanities (DH) researchers which computational resources would (if available) accelerate their research in the years to come.  We called this unicorn “DH’s HuggingFace” in reference to a code library in Python. The Hugging Face library recently boosted various forms of computational research by greatly facilitating the process […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kaspar Beelen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CfP: DHd 2022, 7.- 11.03.2022, Potsdam, Germany]]></title>
        <id>1313 at https://eadh.org</id>
        <link href="https://eadh.org/news/2021/06/09/cfp-dhd-2022-7-11032022-potsdam-germany"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T10:25:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[15 Jul 2021 - 00:00



CfP: DHd 2022, 7.- 11.03.2022, Potsdam, Germany



Dear all,
 
We would like to inform you that submissons are welcome for DHd 2022, 7.- 11.03.2022, at Potsdam, Germany.
DHd 2022 "Kulturen des digitalen Gedächtnisses" is the annual conference of the Verband Digital Humanities im deutschsprachigen Raum, an associative member of the European Association of Digital Humanities (EADH). 
Check out the website (https://www.dhd2022.de) for the Call for Papers (in German) and details about the submission procedure. Please notice that the deadline is 15.07.2021. You can also follow us on Twitter @dhd2022!
Looking forward to welcome you at Potsdam,
 
Ulrike Wuttke
on behalf of the Local Organisers of DHd 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Communication Fellow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digitisation of Smyth’s 1845 ‘Panorama of London’]]></title>
        <id>https://digitalhumanities.exeter.ac.uk/?p=729</id>
        <link href="https://digitalhumanities.exeter.ac.uk/2021/06/digitisation-of-smyths-1845-panorama-of-london/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T14:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are delighted to present an interactive map of the print of Smyth’s Panorama of London held in The Bill Douglas Cinema Museum’s collection (see here: EXEBD 12796): https://humanities-research.exeter.ac.uk/bdcm/panorama/bdcm_bl_complete_storymap.html  In the blog-post below, Ollie Anthony, Technical Assistant at the Digital Humanities Lab and former BDCM museum volunteer, explains the significance of the panorama and the […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Anthony</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[If You Aren’t Happy with the Things Around You; Change the Things Around You.]]></title>
        <id>https://dhlc.cal.msu.edu/?p=292</id>
        <link href="https://dhlc.cal.msu.edu/2021/06/06/if-you-arent-happy-with-the-things-around-you-change-the-things-around-you/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T16:26:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By Mitch Carr Everybody can channel the excitement that comes with serendipitously coming across a work of art proudly showcased in their community. It inspires feelings of nostalgia through storytelling in a multimodal way. And, as I sit at the newly painted picnic tables located in front of Soul Nutrition in Downtown Lansing, I can’t […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>carrmitc</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Job Offer: Professorship (W2-S) for “Historical Educational Research with a Focus on Digital Humanities” at Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin and DIPF]]></title>
        <id>1312 at https://eadh.org</id>
        <link href="https://eadh.org/news/2021/06/05/job-offer-professorship-w2-s-historical-educational-research-focus-digital"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T13:33:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Job Offer: Professorship (W2-S) for “Historical Educational Research with a Focus on Digital Humanities” at Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin and DIPF



The Faculty of Humanities and Social Sciences, Institute for Educational Sciences, of Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin, and Leibniz Institute for Research and Information in Education (DIPF) invite applications for a
Professorship (W2-S) for “Historical Educational Research with a Focus on Digital Humanities”
limited to 5 years, starting as soon as possible.
Applicants should be experienced researchers in the field of German and/or transnational history of education with a focus on or documented interest in epistemological questions and methods of the Digital Humanities. The task of the successful applicant is to develop new uses of Digital Hu…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Communication Fellow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[To Kill and To be Killed: Charting Artistic Change in the Aegean Bronze Age]]></title>
        <id>https://sites.temple.edu/tudsc/?p=7877</id>
        <link href="https://sites.temple.edu/tudsc/2021/06/02/to-kill-and-to-be-killed-charting-artistic-change-in-the-aegean-bronze-age/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T17:14:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By Tenninger Kellenbarger Introduction: As an art historian, I am examining and evaluating the use of the smiting pose in the Aegean Bronze Age while also investigating and tracing the roots of...
The post To Kill and To be Killed: Charting Artistic Change in the Aegean Bronze Age appeared first on Loretta C. Duckworth Scholars Studio.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tenninger Kellenbarger</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Superstate or Tool of Nations? Rethinking the History of European Union]]></title>
        <id>3460 at https://www.c2dh.uni.lu</id>
        <link href="https://www.c2dh.uni.lu/events/superstate-or-tool-nations-rethinking-history-european-union"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T11:17:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today it often appears as though the European Union has entered existential crisis after decades of success, condemned by its adversaries as a bureaucratic monster eroding national sovereignty: at best wasteful, at worst dangerous. How did we reach this point and how has European integration impacted on ordinary people's lives - not just in the member states, but also beyond? This talk will present some of my recent book's findings on the history of the EU.
Kiran Klaus Patel holds the Chair of European History at Ludwig-Maximilians-Universität Munich and is a fellow of the Royal Historical Society. Before joining LMU, he held chairs at Maastricht University (2011-2019) and European University Institute (2007-2011). His book The New Deal: A Global History (Princeton University Press, 2016) won the World History Association Bentley Book Prize. His latest publication Project Europe: A History was published with Cambridge University Press in 2020. His teaching and research focus on issues of European and US American history. Comparative, transnational and global approaches feature prominently in his work
 
Tuesday, 15 June 2021
starting at 5:00 PM CET
Online - Webex
 
For the Webex link please contact Adelina Stefan at oana.stefan@uni.lu.
15 June 2021
  Contemporary history of Europe
  European infrastructures  European integration
  Conferences
  Published  
    Hide image in content detail]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Noëlle Schon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding Institutional use of HTR: Your experience with Transkribus]]></title>
        <id>https://readcoop.eu/?p=24438</id>
        <link href="https://readcoop.eu/understanding-institutional-use-of-htr-your-experience-with-transkribus/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T09:43:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Help us to understand the institutional use of HTR: Joe Nockels is working on this project for his PHD (a Scottish Graduate School of Arts and Humanities (SGSAH) funded PhD). He aims to identify how to incorporate the use of Handwritten Text Recognition (HTR) at scale, working in collaboration with the National Library of Scotland […]
The post Understanding Institutional use of HTR: Your experience with Transkribus appeared first on READ-COOP.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Florian Stauder</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RECAP: Crowdsourcing and the Humanities: Roundtable Discussions Celebrating Scribes of the Cairo Geniza]]></title>
        <id>https://judaicadh.github.io//blog/2021-05-31-scribes-recap/</id>
        <link href="https://judaicadh.github.io//blog/2021-05-31-scribes-recap/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Center for Research Data and Digital Scholarship at University of Pennsylvania Libraries, The Center for Digital Humanities at Princeton University Library, the Princeton Geniza Lab, and the Zooniverse present a series of conversations on project management and development, creation and use of data, and crowdsourcing platforms and research possibilities.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Judaica DH at the Penn Libraries</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blowing the doors off debt: mapping global interactions of a community project]]></title>
        <id>http://blogs.ucl.ac.uk/dh/?p=8178</id>
        <link href="https://blogs.ucl.ac.uk/dh/2021/05/27/blowing-the-doors-off-debt-mapping-global-interactions-of-a-community-project/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T16:44:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The film Bank Job by Daniel Edelstyn and Hilary Powell is an exploration of the world of credit and of capital creation, and the buying and selling of debt. The film follows a community project in which artists Edelstyn and Powell create their own currency, set up as a bank, and sell bank notes in […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver W Duke-Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[“Infrastructural Interventions”: Digital Humanities & Critical Infrastructure Studies Workshop, 21-22nd June 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://blogs.kcl.ac.uk/ddh/?p=3047</id>
        <link href="https://blogs.kcl.ac.uk/ddh/2021/05/27/infrastructural-interventions/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T15:21:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Department of Digital Humanities, King’s Digital Lab and the Critical Infrastructures Studies Initiative (cistudies.org) are co-hosting an event on “Infrastructural Interventions” on 21-22nd June 2021, organised by Urszula Pawlicka-Deger, Marie Curie Research Fellow at King’s. The event includes talks and discussions with Urszula Pawlicka-Deger, Alan Liu, Laura Mandell, Matthew K. Gold, Susan Brown, Lauren … 
Continue reading "“Infrastructural Interventions”: Digital Humanities & Critical Infrastructure Studies Workshop, 21-22nd June 2021"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan Gray</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Different Cultures in Digital History]]></title>
        <id>3425 at https://www.c2dh.uni.lu</id>
        <link href="https://www.c2dh.uni.lu/events/different-cultures-digital-history"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T13:10:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[International Round Table: “Different Cultures in Digital History”
8 June 2021 at 2.30pm (CEST), online
The aim of the round table is to bring together specialists in digital history and experts who use digital tools in historical research and education. History as an academic field is undergoing major changes as a result of the transformative impact of digital technologies. These technologies affect the very nature of sources, the practice of data collection and processing, and also the way in which historical knowledge is acquired and disseminated. The task of defining “digital history” has given rise to much debate and discussion, but developing an understanding of the field and the wide-ranging potential for interaction between history and digital technologies can offer insights into t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Noëlle Schon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DHN2020 Post-Proceedings published]]></title>
        <id>http://dig-hum-nord.eu/?p=1905</id>
        <link href="http://dhnb.eu/dhn2020-post-proceedings/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T12:57:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Post-Proceedings of the 5th Conference Digital Humanities in the Nordic Countries (DHN 2020)  are published in CEUR Workshop Proceedings. It is an open-access publication service where already four volumes of DHN conference proceedings have been published. DHN2020 Post-Proceedings contain 26 papers presented in an online conference in Riga/Zoom in October 2020. Editors: Sanita Reinsone (Institute […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sanita</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CDH Webinar: ‘Mediating sustainable cities: a methodological approach’, presented by Paola Monachesi]]></title>
        <id>1311 at https://eadh.org</id>
        <link href="https://eadh.org/news/2021/05/26/cdh-webinar-mediating-sustainable-cities-methodological-approach-presented-paola"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T07:18:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[28 May 2021 - 00:00



CDH Webinar: ‘Mediating sustainable cities: a methodological approach’, presented by Paola Monachesi



Date/Time
Date(s) - 28-05-2021
15:00 - 16:15
Location
Online
Registration through the following link: Centre for Digital Humanities | CDH Webinar: 'Mediating sustainable cities: a methodological approach', presented by Paola Monachesi (uu.nl)
On 28 May, the Utrecht Centre for Digital Humanities organises a webinar in which Dr Paola Monachesi (Languages, Literature and Communication, Utrecht University) presents a podcast series under development focusing on her research on urban sustainable development.
Environmental sustainability
In her research, Monachesi takes a communication approach to urban sustainable development. She focuses on social behaviour analysed on the basis of communication arising from social media data. She claims that data ownership is key to digital and environmental sustainability.
Social media data
In this webinar Monachesi presents the computational methodology she developed to analyse social media data that exploits the linguistic, communicative and relational characteristics of the users. She focuses on two communities: creative migrants and elderly. In order to reveal the more implicit meaning of the data, she combines her quantitative analysis with a qualitative, thematic analysis in a novel mixed-method approach based on an explanatory sequential emergent design.
Podcast and debate
Attendants will listen to 3 podcasts of about 10-15 mins addressing the methodology. There will be space to ask questions and have a debate about the approach, results of the analysis and the relation between digital and environmental sustainability. Furthermore, there will be the possibility to comment and give feedback on the podcast series.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Communication Fellow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Event: ReproducibiliTea@KULeuven journal club on open data]]></title>
        <id>https://scholarlytales.hcommons.org/?p=687</id>
        <link href="https://scholarlytales.hcommons.org/2021/05/25/event-reproducibiliteakuleuven-journal-club-on-open-data/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T13:14:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The next ReproducibiliTea@KULeuven journal club will take place online on Thursday 17 June (15h00-16h30). Two papers related to open data will be discussed, you can find the papers on the OSF page and Zotero library of ReproducibiliTea. Both staff and students from KU Leuven are welcome to attend (register here). Upon registration, you will receive an e-mail with a link needed to enter the online meeting. More information can be found here (KU Leuven intranet page). ReproducibiliTea is a grassroots journal...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Laura Mesotten</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TEI-C 2021 elections: call for nominations]]></title>
        <id>https://tei-c.org/?p=31043</id>
        <link href="https://tei-c.org/2021/05/25/tei-c-2021-elections-call-for-nominations/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T07:44:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Text Encoding Initiative Consortium (TEI-C) invites nominations for election to the TEI-C Board and the Technical Council. The following positions are vacant and up for election: TEI-C Board 2 members (for 3-year term) TEI-C Council 4 members (for 3-year term) 2 members (for 1-year term) Please submit your nominations to the TEI-C Board Nominating […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martina Scholger</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upcoming Association for Documentary Editing (ADE) virtual conference]]></title>
        <id>1310 at https://eadh.org</id>
        <link href="https://eadh.org/news/2021/05/24/upcoming-association-documentary-editing-ade-virtual-conference"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T16:28:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Upcoming Association for Documentary Editing (ADE) virtual conference



Registration is now open for the Association for Documentary Editing’s 2021 Virtual Conference “Representation and Recovery.” To promote a wide range of conversations, this year’s program will be held in two portions, with an “annual meeting” on 24-27 June, and “conference/networking sessions” on 6, 13, 20, and 27 July. All events will be held virtually. Live sessions will be made available on Zoom, and recordings (where permitted) will be made available on the ADE’s YouTube channel.
Learn more about registration details and see the full schedule of events here. Access the shareable program flyer here.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Communication Fellow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[La poética dramática desde una perspectiva cuantitativa: la obra de Calderón de la Barca]]></title>
        <id>http://revistas.uned.es/index.php/RHD/article/view/27716</id>
        <link href="https://openmethods.dariah.eu/2021/05/24/la-poetica-dramatica-desde-una-perspectiva-cuantitativa-la-obra-de-calderon-de-la-barca/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T11:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction: In this paper, Ehrlicher et al. follow a quantitative approach to unveil possible structural parallelisms between 13 comedies and 10 autos sacramentales written by Calderón de la Barca. Comedies are analyzed within a comparative framework, setting them against Spanish comedia nueva and French comedie precepts. Authors employ tool DramaAnalysis and statistics for their examination, focusing on: word frequency per subgenre, average number of characters, their variation and discourse distribution, etc. Autos sacramentales are also evaluated through these indicators. Regarding comedies, Ehrlicher et al.’s results show that Calderón: a) plays with units of space and time depending on creative and dramatic needs, b) does not follow French comedie conventions of character intervention or linkage, but c) does abide by its concept of structural symmetry. As for autos sacramentales, their findings brought forth that these have a similar length and character variation to comedies. However, they also identified the next difference: Calderón uses character co-presence in them to reinforce the message conveyed. Considering all this, authors confirm that Calderón’s comedies disassociate from classical notions of theatre – both Aristotelian and French –ideals. With respect to autos sacramentales, they believe further evaluation would be needed to verify ideas put forward and identify other structural patterns.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Author on Source</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NAA RecordSearch section of the GLAM Workbench updated!]]></title>
        <id>http://wragge.micro.blog/2021/05/24/naa-recordsearch-section.html</id>
        <link href="https://updates.timsherratt.org/2021/05/24/naa-recordsearch-section.html"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T00:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you work with the collections of the National Archives of Australia, you might find the RecordSearch section of the GLAM Workbench helpful. I’ve just updated the repository to add new options for running the notebooks, including 1-click installation on Reclaim Cloud. There’s also a few new notebooks.
New notebooks and datasets
Harvest details of all series in RecordSearch – get details of all series registered in RecordSearch, also generates a summary dataset with the total number of items digitised, described and in each access category
Exploring harvested series data  – generates some basic statistics from the harvest of series data
Summary data about all series in RecordSearch  (15mb CSV) – contains basic descriptive information about all the series currently registered on RecordSearch (May 2021) as well as the total number of items described, digitised, and in each access category

Updated
I’ve started (but not completed) updating all the notebooks in this repository to use my new RecordSearch Data Scraper. The new scraper is simpler and more efficient, and enables me to get rid of a lot of boilerplate code. Updated notebooks include:
Harvest items from a search in RecordSearch – save the results of an item search in RecordSearch as a downloadable dataset, you can also save images and PDFs from digitised files (PDF saving is new!)
Harvest files with the access status of ‘closed’ – find out what we’re not allowed to see by harvesting details of ‘closed’ files
Other updates include:
Python packages updated
Integration with Reclaim Cloud allowing 1-click installation of the whole repository and environment
Automatic creation of Docker images when the repository is updated
Updated README and repository index with list of all notebooks
Notebooks intended to run as apps now use Voila rather than Appmode for better integration with Jupyter Lab
requirements-unpinned.txt added to repository for people who want to develop the notebooks in their own clean environment
Hope you find these changes useful! #dhhacks]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Sherratt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ESC’s Statement on Proposed Cuts to Higher Education Funding for Archaeology in the UK]]></title>
        <id>https://sites.caa-international.org/main/?p=15701</id>
        <link href="https://caa-international.org/2021/05/23/escs-statement-on-proposed-cuts-to-higher-education-funding-for-archaeology-in-the-uk/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T15:24:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The International Society for Computer Applications and Quantitative Methods in Archaeology (CAA) represents researchers, professionals and students working in diverse capacities to bring together the strengths of digital, computational and quantitative methods with creative, critical and impactful archaeological and heritage … Continue reading →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeffrey Glover</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Computer-based Text and Discourse Analysis]]></title>
        <id>32937 at http://digihum.ut.ee</id>
        <link href="http://digihum.ut.ee/event/computer-based-text-and-discourse-analysis"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T07:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Asukoht: 

Zoom



Järgmisel reedel, 21. mail, kl 10.15 -12 (zoomis) tutvustab Tartu Ülikooli maailma keelte ja kultuuride kolledži võõrkeelte erialase digipädevuse arendamise projekti raames Laurent Vanni, (...
 Loe lähemalt Computer-based Text and Discourse Analysis kohta]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>a71389</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digitising Industrial Heritage]]></title>
        <id>3418 at https://www.c2dh.uni.lu</id>
        <link href="https://www.c2dh.uni.lu/events/digitising-industrial-heritage"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T06:00:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The legacy of industrialisation has resulted in “place[s] longing for historical self-assurance” (Achim Saupe). The current focus on industrial heritage has resulted in efforts to preserve and reconstruct this heritage in its original state. This applies not only to the memory of former workplaces, homes and recreation areas in post-industrial places, but also to the biographies of entrepreneurs, industrial workers and their families. The preservation and musealisation of former industrial landscapes raise further questions about the authenticity of such places. Public history, and with it the representation of the industrial past in museums, exhibitions and events, is situated between “original” representation and recreated staging. Furthermore, and this has been accelerated by the COVID-…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Noëlle Schon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Civil War & Reconstruction Governors of Alabama]]></title>
        <id>https://adhc.lib.ua.edu/?p=727</id>
        <link href="https://adhc.lib.ua.edu/cwrga/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T19:49:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Civil War and Reconstruction Era was a period of great change and strife for the state of Alabama and the nation.  Documents included...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>adhcadmin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alabama Shakespeare Project]]></title>
        <id>https://adhc.lib.ua.edu/?p=724</id>
        <link href="https://adhc.lib.ua.edu/alabama-shakespeare-project/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T19:47:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Alabama Shakespeare Project (ASP) is a performance-based research collective exploring early modern entertainments. To do so, we  stage free...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>adhcadmin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Religion & Science: Creating Health in 19th Century U.S.]]></title>
        <id>https://adhc.lib.ua.edu/?p=717</id>
        <link href="https://adhc.lib.ua.edu/rel120/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T19:43:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In Spring 2021, Dr. Jeri Wieringa’s REL120 class created a course website featuring exhibits and mapping to study religion and...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>adhcadmin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PSC344]]></title>
        <id>https://adhc.lib.ua.edu/?p=715</id>
        <link href="https://adhc.lib.ua.edu/psc344-the-israel-palestine-conflict/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T19:40:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This project was created to showcase Dr. Daniel Levine’s Fall 2020 PSC344.001 – The Israel/Palestine Conflict course to showcase his...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>adhcadmin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Join us for an (en)coding Heritage Seminar Series!]]></title>
        <id>1308 at https://eadh.org</id>
        <link href="https://eadh.org/news/2021/05/18/join-us-encoding-heritage-seminar-series"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T17:47:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Join us for an (en)coding Heritage Seminar Series! 



The (en)coding Heritage Seminar Series brings together researchers who are working at the cutting edge of digital technologies, humanities and heritage science. Each session will consist of several presentations describing ongoing projects in the field. Topics include digital mapping projects, data visualisation, digital art history/digital visual studies, digital restorations, and new mobile applications for the recoding of architecture and cultural heritage.
The seminar will take place on the following dates:
New Directions in Digital Visual Studies, 27 May 2021, 5 pm (BST)
Mapping Real and Imagined Sites, 10 June 2021, 5pm (BST)
Immersive Technologies in Education, 17 June 2021, 5pm (BST).
The full programme will be published here in due course.
Register for one event or the entire series using the following form:
https://durhamuniversity.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_To6vV0NBR3Wq_T4Ejbslwg
Organised by the (en)coding Heritage in collaboration with Leonardo Impett (Durham University).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Communication Fellow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Book: ’Yesterday’s News: The Future of Long-form Journalism and Archives’]]></title>
        <id>https://blogs.kcl.ac.uk/ddh/?p=3028</id>
        <link href="https://blogs.kcl.ac.uk/ddh/2021/05/18/yesterdays-news-the-future-of-long-form-journalism-and-archives/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T14:15:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new book by Marco Braghieri entitled ‘Yesterday’s News – The future of long-form journalism and archives’ has been published by Peter Lang. The book focuses on two entities (long-form journalism and archives) which sit at the intersection between journalistic production and the digital. While framed within digital humanities, this book deploys a number of … 
Continue reading "New Book: ’Yesterday’s News: The Future of Long-form Journalism and Archives’"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marco Braghieri</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arabic Collections Online (ACO)]]></title>
        <id>https://scholarlytales.hcommons.org/?p=526</id>
        <link href="https://scholarlytales.hcommons.org/2021/05/18/arabic-collections-online-aco/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T08:46:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The project Arabic Collections Online (ACO) is an online library specialized in providing Open Access to Arabic books and manuscripts in several scientific domains. ACO started its digitization project with the aim of providing free and global access to Arabic language content, which is currently not widely available. The project already offers access to over 16.000 volumes, however the goal of the project is to digitize 23.000 Arabic volumes. The topics range from philosophy and religion to political sciences and...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hanna Van Heesvelde</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Article: Maps of a Nation]]></title>
        <id>https://livingwithmachines.ac.uk/?p=1881</id>
        <link href="https://livingwithmachines.ac.uk/new-article-maps-of-a-nation/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=new-article-maps-of-a-nation"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T19:46:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We have published a new Open Access article in the Journal of Victorian Culture about using Computer Vision with historical maps. ‘Maps of a Nation?’ describes our Computer Vision pipeline for working with thousands of maps at once, which enables new forms of historical inquiry based on spatial analysis. The Ordnance Survey has been the […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katie McDonough</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Event: Integrating Citizen Science at Universities: From ‘What’ to ‘How’]]></title>
        <id>https://scholarlytales.hcommons.org/?p=671</id>
        <link href="https://scholarlytales.hcommons.org/2021/05/17/event-integrating-citizen-science-at-universities-from-what-to-how/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T07:08:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On 2 and 4 June, LIBER (Ligue des Bibliothèques Européennes de Recherche – Association of European Research Libraries) will organize a Citizen Science workshop at KU Leuven. The workshop will be of a highly participatory nature, with participants required to work in small groups during their own time. The first session will take place on the 2nd of June from 10.00-11.30 (CEST), followed by a second session on the 4th of June from 14.00-15.30 (CEST). Important to note: once registered, you are required to...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Laura Mesotten</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Undogmatic Literary Annotation with CATMA in: Annotations in Scholarly Editions and Research]]></title>
        <id>https://www.degruyter.com/view/book/9783110689112/10.1515/9783110689112-008.xml</id>
        <link href="https://openmethods.dariah.eu/2021/05/17/undogmatic-literary-annotation-with-catma-in-annotations-in-scholarly-editions-and-research/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T05:46:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction: Digital Literary Studies has long engaged with the challenges in representing ambiguity, contradiction and polyvocal readings of literary texts. This book chapter describes a web-based tool called CATMA which  promises a "low-threshold" approach to digitally encoded text interpretation. CATMA has a long trajectory based on a 'standoff' approach to markup, somewhat provocatively described by its creators as "undogmatic", which stands in contrast to more established systems for text representation in digital scholarly editing and publishing such as XML markup, or the Text Encoding Initiative (TEI). Standoff markup involves applying numbers to each character of a text and then using those numbers as identifiers to store interpretation externally. This approach allows for "multip…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Author on Source</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web archives section of GLAM Workbench updated!]]></title>
        <id>http://wragge.micro.blog/2021/05/17/web-archives-section.html</id>
        <link href="https://updates.timsherratt.org/2021/05/17/web-archives-section.html"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T02:22:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[My program of rolling out new features and integrations across the GLAM Workbench continues. The latest section to be updated is the Web Archives section!
There are no new notebooks with this update, but some important changes under the hood. If you haven’t used it before, the Web Archives section contains 16 notebooks providing documentation, tools, apps, and examples to help you make use of web archives in your research. The notebooks are grouped by the following topics: Types of data, Harvesting data and creating datasets, and Exploring change over time.

I’ve updated all the Python packages used in this repository and changed the app-ified notebooks to run using Voila (which is better integrated with Jupyter Lab than Appmode). But most importantly, you can now install the repository into your own persistent environment using Reclaim Cloud or Docker.
As Christie Moffatt noted recently harvesting data from web archives can take a long time, and you might hit the limits of the free Binder service. These new integrations mean you don’t have to worry about your notebooks timing out. Just click on the Launch on Reclaim Cloud button and you can have your own fully-provisioned, persistent environment up and running in minutes!

This is possible because every change to the Web Archives repository now triggers the build of a new Docker image with all the software that you need pre-installed. You can also run this Docker image on your own computer, or using another cloud service.
The Web Archives section now includes documentation on running the notebooks using Binder, Reclaim, Cloud or Docker. #dhhacks]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Sherratt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Mapping to Explore Black Philadelphia’s Historic Landmarks]]></title>
        <id>https://sites.temple.edu/tudsc/?p=7901</id>
        <link href="https://sites.temple.edu/tudsc/2021/05/14/digital-mapping-to-explore-black-philadelphias-historic-landmarks/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T23:27:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By Tauheedah Asad Introduction As a media and communications doctoral student, I have an interest in exploring how digital tools can be utilized to make research and information accessible to mass audiences....
The post Digital Mapping to Explore Black Philadelphia’s Historic Landmarks appeared first on Loretta C. Duckworth Scholars Studio.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tauheedah Asad</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using GIS to Map Settler Colonialism in Pennsylvania]]></title>
        <id>https://sites.temple.edu/tudsc/?p=7867</id>
        <link href="https://sites.temple.edu/tudsc/2021/05/14/using-gis-to-map-settler-colonialism-in-pennsylvania/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T17:08:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By Ryan Wheatley In this blog post, I will detail my digital project to create a historic GIS landscape map focusing on the expansion of British and later American settlements (1680-1900’s) across...
The post Using GIS to Map Settler Colonialism in Pennsylvania appeared first on Loretta C. Duckworth Scholars Studio.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ryan Wheatley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EADH Elections 2021 - Participation Requirements]]></title>
        <id>1307 at https://eadh.org</id>
        <link href="https://eadh.org/news/2021/05/14/eadh-elections-2021-participation-requirements"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T16:29:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[11 Jun 2021 - 00:00



EADH Elections 2021 - Participation Requirements



Dear colleagues,
This message concerns the forthcoming EADH Elections.
Thank you for your continued support of EADH and its Associate Organisations. This is to remind you that elections for new members of the EADH Executive Committee will be held prior to the EADH AGM 2021.
Those wishing to take part in the elections as voters or candidates must be Members in Good Standing (i.e. have paid their membership fees) by June 11th, whether as a direct or joint member of EADH, or through one of its Associate Organizations:

AIUCD (Associazione Informatica Umanistica e Cultura Digitale)
CzADH (Česká asociace pro digitální humanitní vědy)
DHd (Digital Humanities im deutschsprachigen Raum)
DHNB (Digital Humanities in the Northern and Baltic countries)
DHRussia (Российская ассоциация цифровых гуманитарных наук)
For information on renewing membership fees, please see https://eadh.org/membership or consult the website of your Association. Each member must assure that the email address used  is not already in use for another registration in the realm of EADH (AOs and DSH subscription).
We will circulate more information about the election process later in the year.
 In the meantime, if you are interested in standing as an Executive Committee member please don't hesitate to contact us at <nominations@eadh.org>.
 
Best regards,
On behalf of the EADH Elections committee
Anna-Maria Sichani 
Marieke van Erp
Joris van Zundert
Barbara Bordalejo
Mikko Tolonen]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Communication Fellow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Call for Executive Board and Committee Chair Applications]]></title>
        <id>588762 at https://adho.org</id>
        <link href="https://adho.org/2021-cfa-eb-chairs"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T16:29:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[**UPDATE: The application/nomination deadline has been extended to 15 June 2021.**
The Alliance of Digital Humanities Organizations (ADHO) seeks applications for the following positions from committed individuals who would like to participate in Digital Humanities leadership on a global scale:
Awards Committee Chair
Conference Coordinating Committee Adjunct Chair-Elect
Executive Board Chair-Elect
Treasurer-Elect
All positions begin 1 July 2021. Term lengths vary by position. Selected applicants will be appointed to only one position.
Background
ADHO is a formal alliance of independent Digital Humanities (DH) organizations that operate in diverse scholarly, cultural, and legal circumstances. Its primary remit is to support DH community activity at a global level and in regions that are not …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>drupaladmin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Registration OPEN for CSDH-SCHN 2021: Making the Net Work / Les inscriptions sont OUVERTES pour CSDH-SCHN 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://csdh-schn.org/?p=707</id>
        <link href="https://csdh-schn.org/conference2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T03:49:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[La version française suit Registration is now OPEN for CSDH-SCHN 2021: Making the Net Work ⏰  Peruse the schedule ⏰📝 Renew your membership 📝🎉 Register now 🎉 This year, CSDH-SCHN features plenty of intellectual stimulation and fun!  Morning ...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Huculak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using web archives to find out when newspapers were added to Trove]]></title>
        <id>http://wragge.micro.blog/2021/05/12/using-web-archives.html</id>
        <link href="https://updates.timsherratt.org/2021/05/12/using-web-archives.html"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T01:36:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s no doubt that Trove’s digitised newspapers have had a significant impact on the practice of history in Australia. But analysing that impact is difficult when Trove itself is always changing – more newspapers and articles are being added all the time.
In an attempt to chart the development of Trove, I’ve created a dataset that shows (approximately) when particular newspaper titles were first added. This gives a rough snapshot of what Trove contained at any point in the last 12 years.

I say approximately because the only public source of this information are web archives like the Internet Archive’s Wayback Machine and Trove itself. By downloading captures of Trove’s browse page, I was able to extract a list of newspaper titles available when that capture was made. Depending on the frequency of captures, the titles may have been first made available some time earlier.
The method I used to create the dataset is documented in the Trove Newspapers section of the GLAM Workbench. I used the Internet Archive as my source rather than Trove just because there were more captures available. Most of the code I could conveniently copy from the Web Archives section of the GLAM Workbench, in particular the Find all the archived versions of a particular web page notebook.
The result was actually two datasets:
trove_newspaper_titles_2009_2021.csv  – complete dataset of captures and titles
trove_newspaper_titles_first_appearance_2009_2021.csv  – filtered dataset, showing only the first appearance of each title / place / date range combination
There’s also an alphabetical list of newspaper titles for easy browsing. The list shows the date of the capture in which the title was first recorded, as well as any changes to its date range. #dhhacks]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Sherratt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Singing Box 331]]></title>
        <id>13c711f2-2059-4336-890f-193a0c2cf912</id>
        <link href="https://reviewsindh.pubpub.org/pub/singing-box-331"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T21:58:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A review of Singing Box 331, a project examining a pamphlet of Mohican-language hymn texts from the 1740s, created by Rachel Wheeler and Sarah Eyerly]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kate Galloway</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Novels in distant reading: the European Literary Text Collection (ELTeC).]]></title>
        <id>http://openmethods.dariah.eu/?p=2967</id>
        <link href="https://openmethods.dariah.eu/2021/05/11/novels-in-distant-reading-the-european-literary-text-collection-eltec/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:32:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction: Among the most recent, currently ongoing, projects exploiting distant techniques reading there is the European Literary Text Collection (ELTeC), which is one of the main elements of the Distant Reading for European Literary History (COST Action CA16204, https://www.distant-reading.net/). Thanks to the contribution provided by four Working Groups (respectively dealing with Scholarly Resources, Methods and Tools, Literary Theory and History, and Dissemination: https://www.distant-reading.net/working-groups/ ), the project aims at providing at least 2,500 novels written in ten European languages with a range of Distant Reading computational tools and methodological strategies to approach them from various perspectives (textual, stylistic, topical, et similia). A full description of the objectives of the Action and of ELTeC can be found and read in the Memorandum of Understanding for the implementation of the COST Action “Distant Reading for European Literary History” (DISTANT-READING) CA 16204”, available at the link  https://e-services.cost.eu/files/domain_files/CA/Action_CA16204/mou/CA16204-e.pdf

[Click ‘Read more’ for the full post!]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marinella Testori</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Registration for CAA 2021 OPEN]]></title>
        <id>https://sites.caa-international.org/main/?p=15692</id>
        <link href="https://caa-international.org/2021/05/10/registration-for-caa-2021-open/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T18:19:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Registration for CAA 2021 is now open. Please click here to be taken to the registration page.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeffrey Glover</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[360° Reich – een webtentoonstelling]]></title>
        <id>https://scholarlytales.hcommons.org/?p=659</id>
        <link href="https://scholarlytales.hcommons.org/2021/05/10/360-reich-een-webtentoonstelling/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T15:02:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MATRIX [Centrum voor Nieuwe Muziek] zet mijlpalen in de muziekgeschiedenis sinds 1950 in de kijker met grote en kleinere tentoonstellingen. De webtentoonstelling Steve Reich 360° (www.stevereichexpo.be) is de meest recente verwezenlijking, en de eerste 100% online tentoonstelling. De expo werd ontwikkeld op vraag van Muziekcentrum De Bijloke Gent en sluit aan bij de concertprogrammering in seizoen 2020-21 met als één van de sleutelfiguren de Amerikaanse componist Steve Reich. Omwille van de coronamaatregelen werkten we het project volledig digitaal uit. We...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Melissa Portaels</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Supporting Future Scholars: The Transkribus Scholarship Programme]]></title>
        <id>https://readcoop.eu/?p=23690</id>
        <link href="https://readcoop.eu/supporting-future-scholars-the-transkribus-scholarship-programme/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Imagine you are a student who wants to dive into the personal story of one of the few famous child authors in history; or who wants to discover what made the authors of the Spanish Golden Age of theatre tick; or you are a teacher who wants to help the future generation in the digital […]
The post Supporting Future Scholars: The Transkribus Scholarship Programme appeared first on READ-COOP.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Florian Stauder</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Editors' Note: May 2021]]></title>
        <id>96a31db9-df7b-46db-a0b2-7283f4b92b0e</id>
        <link href="https://reviewsindh.pubpub.org/pub/ed-note-may-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Editors' note on the May 2021 issue of Reviews in Digital Humanities]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Roopika Risam</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Visualizing Objects, Places, and Spaces]]></title>
        <id>bf2d3fa7-41da-4355-91e0-47115f9a19ff</id>
        <link href="https://reviewsindh.pubpub.org/pub/visualizing-objects-places-and-spaces"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A review of Visualizing Objects, Places, and Spaces, a compendium of resources for all stages of digital project development, created by Beth Fischer and Hannah Jacobs]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brandon Walsh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Land and Legacy]]></title>
        <id>700222b0-7b2f-4186-8087-cc1b4e5f9fa0</id>
        <link href="https://reviewsindh.pubpub.org/pub/land-and-legacy"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A review of Land and Legacy, a project investigating the University of Virginia’s land expansion since the 1980s, directed by Janet S. Dunkelbarger, Connor Kenaston, Natasha Roth-Rowland, Lauren Van Nest, and Chloe Down Wells]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Claire A. Tratnyek</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Mapping Marronage]]></title>
        <id>bf990101-17db-4bde-9754-ee94042a0995</id>
        <link href="https://reviewsindh.pubpub.org/pub/mapping-marronage"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A review of Mapping Marronage, an interactive project examining the mobility of enslaved people in the 18th and 19th centuries, directed by Annette Joseph-Gabriel]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shavagne Scott</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: GeoNewsMiner]]></title>
        <id>079f1918-eaaa-4787-8a0e-2e44e7e77d47</id>
        <link href="https://reviewsindh.pubpub.org/pub/geonewsminer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A review of GeoNewsMiner, an app visualizing geographical references in historical newspapers, created by Lorella Viola and Jaap Verheul]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Avery Blankenship</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Event: DHSITE2021 with workshops on Python, Linked Open Data, Text Analysis, and Machine Translation]]></title>
        <id>https://scholarlytales.hcommons.org/?p=652</id>
        <link href="https://scholarlytales.hcommons.org/2021/05/07/event-dhsite2021-with-workshops-on-python-linked-open-data-text-analysis-and-machine-translation/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T07:41:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DHSITE 2021 is taking place the weeks of May 17-21 and May 24-28. In this two-week period, they organize 18-hour micro-course workshops. Workshop topics include an Introduction to Python (in English and in French), Issues in Digital Humanities, Introduction to Linked Open Data, Text Analysis, and Machine Translation. The detailed program can be found on the event website. Registration is open! Be sure to reserve your spot. Micro-course workshops with low pre-registration will be cancelled. Additionally, part of DHSITE 2021, the...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Laura Mesotten</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get new Scholarly Tales posts in Outlook via the blog’s RSS feed]]></title>
        <id>https://scholarlytales.hcommons.org/?p=642</id>
        <link href="https://scholarlytales.hcommons.org/2021/05/05/get-new-scholarly-tales-posts-in-outlook-via-the-blogs-rss-feed/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T09:20:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Would you like to stay up to date with new posts on the Scholarly Tales blog right from Outlook? RSS, or Really Simple Syndication, is “a web feed that allows users and applications to access updates to websites in a standardized, computer-readable format” (Wikipedia). Blogs and many other online resources, including academic journals and databases, often offer RSS feeds of their new content. By subscribing to RSS feeds, you can get updates from many sources delivered in one location. Where...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nele Noppe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Finding an Open Access journal with the DOAJ]]></title>
        <id>https://scholarlytales.hcommons.org/?p=612</id>
        <link href="https://scholarlytales.hcommons.org/2021/05/05/finding-an-open-access-journal-with-the-doaj/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T07:52:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking to publish in Open Access but not sure how to find a suitable Open Access journal in your specific discipline? The easiest way to start your search is browsing through the Directory of Open Access Journals (DOAJ), which was created to increase the accessibility, usage, and impact of quality OA resources. The DOAJ indexes academic journals across all disciplines that are peer-reviewed and only have the Full OA-option, not the Hybrid OA-option. If you already have a specific journal...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Laura Bervoets</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Short introduction to navigating Limo]]></title>
        <id>https://scholarlytales.hcommons.org/?p=438</id>
        <link href="https://scholarlytales.hcommons.org/2021/05/04/short-introduction-to-navigating-limo/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T10:22:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Limo is the discovery service that allows you to search the entire KU Leuven Libraries collection. It is made up of an extensive collection of both printed and electronic resources. So with one search you will not only find all physical items (e.g. print books, journals, newspapers) available in KU Leuven Libraries but also scientific output from the university’s researchers, which are collected in Lirias, and a vast selection of e-resources, such as electronic books, journals, databases, and also audio-visual...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Laura Bervoets</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trial access: Eustathius, Commentary on the Iliad/Odyssey (Brill Scholarly Editions)]]></title>
        <id>https://scholarlytales.hcommons.org/?p=574</id>
        <link href="https://scholarlytales.hcommons.org/2021/05/03/trial-access-eustathius-commentary-on-the-iliad-odyssey-brill-scholarly-editions/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T16:01:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Until 25 May 2021 KU Leuven users have trial access to two new sources on the Brill Scholarly Editions platform: Eustathius of Thessalonica: Commentary on the Iliad This is the online version of the complete critical edition by Marchinus van der Valk of Eusthathius of Thessalonica’s Commentary on the Iliad, composed during the latter half of the twelfth century CE, published in hard copy by Brill between 1971–1987. Eustathius of Thessalonica: Commentary on the Odyssey This online publication (to be...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nele Baplu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Aphra Behn: The Podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://adhc.lib.ua.edu/?p=610</id>
        <link href="https://adhc.lib.ua.edu/aphra-behn-the-podcast/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T13:21:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author, spy, political propagandist, Aphra Behn (1640–1689) was one of the first English women to earn a living by her pen. Set against...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>adhcadmin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Language Interpretability Tool: Extensible, Interactive Visualizations and Analysis for NLP Models]]></title>
        <id>https://arxiv.org/abs/2008.05122v1</id>
        <link href="https://openmethods.dariah.eu/2021/04/29/2008-05122-the-language-interpretability-tool-extensible-interactive-visualizations-and-analysis-for-nlp-models/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-29T09:58:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction: NLP modelling and tasks performed by them are becoming an integral part of our daily realities (everyday or research). A central concern of NLP research is that for many of their users, these models still largely operate as black boxes with limited reflections on why the model makes certain predictions, how their usage is skewed towards certain content types, what are the underlying social, cultural biases etc.  The open source Language Interoperability Tool  aim to change this for the better and brings transparency to the visualization and understanding of NLP models. The pre-print describing the tool comes with rich documentation and description of the tool (including case studies of different kinds) and gives us an honest SWOT analysis of it.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Author on Source</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Portraits in DH: Dr. Sylvia Fernández]]></title>
        <id>https://ach.org/?p=2207</id>
        <link href="https://ach.org/blog/2021/04/25/portraits-in-dh-dr-sylvia-fernandez/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-25T13:47:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Interviewed on March 9, 2021 by Anna E. Kijas Sylvia A. Fernández, Ph.D is currently a Public and Digital Humanities Postdoctoral Fellow at the Hall Center for the Humanities, University of Kansas. She is a co-founder of Borderlands Archives Cartography, a member of Torn Apart / Separados, and team member and coordinator of the ongoing initiative of United Fronteras, as well…Continue reading.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jwoowinter</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Technology & the Historian: Transformations of the Digital Age’ Workshop & Book Launch]]></title>
        <id>http://blogs.ucl.ac.uk/dh/?p=8172</id>
        <link href="https://blogs.ucl.ac.uk/dh/2021/04/23/technology-the-historian-transformations-of-the-digital-age-workshop-book-launch/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-23T09:27:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lessons from history, options for today. Thursday 29 April 2021 – 12pm-1pm (Zoom) Register for free. Join Dr. Adam Crymble for a free Programming Historian Teaching Workshop to celebrate the launch of his new book, Technology & the Historian: Transformations of the Digital Age, the first comprehensive history of historical studies in the digital age. […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>uczcrym</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day of DH 2021; Mid-Atlantic Edition]]></title>
        <id>https://dh.rutgers.edu/?p=77252</id>
        <link href="https://dh.rutgers.edu/day-of-dh-2021/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=day-of-dh-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-04-21T19:47:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[#dayofDH2021 is finally here, hosted by @LUCTSDH, @UCLA_DH, University of Guelph, and the Università del Piedmont Orientale. Date: April 29. Theme: Multilingual DH. Head over to https://t.co/78PFzqGDlL for details and stay tuned for more! https://t.co/LYTfwjNE2h — Day of DH (@DayofDH) April 4, 2021 Attention digital humanists of Princeton, Rutgers, Bryn Mawr, Haverford, Swarthmore, and the Mid-Atlantic. Join us for Day of Digital Humanities 2021 by tweeting about your multilingual DH. The aim of this year’s Day of DH is to “open up conversation about projects being undertaken in the various languages and put together a list of non-English tools, libraries, software products, tips, hacks, and]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Francesca Giannetti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EVENT: Crowdsourcing and the Humanities: Roundtable Discussions Celebrating Scribes of the Cairo Geniza]]></title>
        <id>https://judaicadh.github.io//blog/2021-04-21-celebrating-scribes/</id>
        <link href="https://judaicadh.github.io//blog/2021-04-21-celebrating-scribes/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-21T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Center for Research Data and Digital Scholarship at University of Pennsylvania Libraries, The Center for Digital Humanities at Princeton University Library, the Princeton Geniza Lab, and the Zooniverse present a series of conversations on project management and development, creation and use of data, and crowdsourcing platforms and research possibilities.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Judaica DH at the Penn Libraries</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New release: Guidelines 4.2.2 / Stylesheets 7.51.2]]></title>
        <id>https://tei-c.org/?p=30971</id>
        <link href="https://tei-c.org/2021/04/19/new-release-guidelines-4-2-2-stylesheets-7-51-2/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-19T13:55:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The TEI Consortium has released version 4.2.2 of the TEI P5 Guidelines and version 7.51.2 of Styelsheets, a follow-up version of the TEI P5 Guidelines version 4.2.1 and Stylesheets version 7.51.1, where an issue was noticed concerning the controlled value lists of certain type attributes. For more details, please see the release notes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martina Scholger</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Ethnography, Where Art Thou?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.vanderbilt.edu/digitalhumanities/?p=3118</id>
        <link href="https://www.vanderbilt.edu/digitalhumanities/digital-ethnography-where-art-thou/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-16T16:30:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By Ashley Kim, Mellon Graduate Student Fellow from the Department of Sociology As an ethnographer, I started my current project the way all brilliant researchers do: inspired by an intriguing research question that popped into my head right as I hit the pillow at night… or in the shower? One of the two. I was...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>forehamj</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kevadised seminarid digihumanitaarias / digilabor. Huvi üleskutse]]></title>
        <id>32287 at http://digihum.ut.ee</id>
        <link href="http://digihum.ut.ee/event/kevadised-seminarid-digihumanitaarias-digilabor-huvi-%C3%BCleskutse"/>
        <updated>2021-04-15T21:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[...
 Loe lähemalt Kevadised seminarid digihumanitaarias / digilabor. Huvi üleskutse kohta]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>a71389</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Georgian and Hungarian speaking data assistants needed on the DH project at King’s]]></title>
        <id>https://blogs.kcl.ac.uk/ddh/?p=3018</id>
        <link href="https://blogs.kcl.ac.uk/ddh/2021/04/14/georgian-and-hungarian-speaking-data-assistants-needed-on-the-dh-project-at-kings/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-14T11:35:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are hiring Georgian and Hungarian speaking data assistants for short-term positions to work on the cross-linguistic project ‘Distant Reading across Languages’ (https://www.kdl.kcl.ac.uk/our-work/distant-reading/). The deadline of applying is 15th May 2021. Please apply via King’s Talent Bank here: https://www.kingstalentbank.com/jobs/show/11217/georgian-speaking-data-assistant-on-dh-project https://www.kingstalentbank.com/jobs/show/11218/hungarian-speaking-data-assistant-on-dh-project If you have any questions about the positions, do not hesitate to contact Dr Gabriele … 
Continue reading "Georgian and Hungarian speaking data assistants needed on the DH project at King’s"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gabriele Salciute Civiliene</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Marking work available at KCL in digital media & technology + digital culture]]></title>
        <id>https://blogs.kcl.ac.uk/ddh/?p=3008</id>
        <link href="https://blogs.kcl.ac.uk/ddh/2021/04/13/marking-work-available-at-kcl-in-digital-media-technology-digital-culture/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-13T09:42:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Department of Digital Humanities at King’s College London is looking for hourly paid lecturers to mark essay assignments in the areas of: digital societies and platforms digital economy & innovation internet culture social media and marketing games and virtual realities digital content management digital curation in cultural institutions. Most assignments are generally 4,000 words … 
Continue reading "Marking work available at KCL in digital media & technology + digital culture"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mercedes Bunz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Mapping the Gay Guides]]></title>
        <id>08f7ce73-b923-4908-9f86-57b151bc4eb1</id>
        <link href="https://reviewsindh.pubpub.org/pub/mapping-the-gay-guides"/>
        <updated>2021-04-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A review of Mapping the Gay Guides, a project mapping  data from Bob Damron’s Address Books, created by Amanda Regan and Eric Gonzaba]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katherin Tairo-Quispe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Collective Biographies of Women]]></title>
        <id>3940ec72-e88e-4166-b9c4-eabb1c8d55e3</id>
        <link href="https://reviewsindh.pubpub.org/pub/collective-biographies-of-women"/>
        <updated>2021-04-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A review of Collective Biographies of Women, a project dedicated to the prosopography of women from books published in the late 19th and early 20th centuries, created by Alison Booth]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ali Gunnells</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Lesbian and Gay Liberation in Canada]]></title>
        <id>a1bfe606-471d-4ff0-8adc-6d647628408c</id>
        <link href="https://reviewsindh.pubpub.org/pub/lesbian-gay-liberation-canada"/>
        <updated>2021-04-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A review of Lesbian and Gay Liberation in Canada, an interactive digital resource for the study of lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, and queer (LGBTQ+) history in Canada from 1964 to 1981, directed by Constance Crompton and Michelle Schwartz]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Becky Yatsuknenko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Readux]]></title>
        <id>7b4cd2c9-e421-4129-b8bd-29e3c5400b7c</id>
        <link href="https://reviewsindh.pubpub.org/pub/readux"/>
        <updated>2021-04-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A review of Readux, an open source software platform for digitized texts, directed by Rebecca Sutton Koeser]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Lacitignola</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Distant Viewing Toolkit]]></title>
        <id>01fedc58-16f3-4a91-9195-1e4bca191f30</id>
        <link href="https://reviewsindh.pubpub.org/pub/distant-viewing-toolkit"/>
        <updated>2021-04-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A review of the Distant Viewing Toolkit, a software library for computational analysis of visual culture, developed by Taylor Arnold and Lauren Tilton]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Sui</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Benefits of Research Collaboration]]></title>
        <id>https://www.vanderbilt.edu/digitalhumanities/?p=3110</id>
        <link href="https://www.vanderbilt.edu/digitalhumanities/the-benefits-of-research-collaboration/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-07T18:47:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Benefits of Research Collaboration By Holly McCammon, Cornelius Vanderbilt Chair of Sociology and Professor of Sociology, Mellon Faculty Fellow I can imagine your frustration as you realize that the user-friendly and, yes, simplified software you’ve been using is no longer meeting your research needs.  Previously, it had been so helpful, as the software guided...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>forehamj</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DHNB2022]]></title>
        <id>http://dig-hum-nord.eu/?p=1885</id>
        <link href="http://dhnb.eu/dhnb2022/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-06T08:57:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 6th Digital Humanities in the Nordic and Baltic Countries Conference (DHNB 2022) will be held at Uppsala University, in Sweden, on 15–18 March 2022. DHNB conferences focus on research, education and communication in the interdisciplinary field of digital humanities in the Nordic and Baltic regions and beyond. DHNB 2022 highlights the two way relationship between digital humanities […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Olga Holownia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating a 3D Map of an Archaeological Site in Blender]]></title>
        <id>https://sites.temple.edu/tudsc/?p=7760</id>
        <link href="https://sites.temple.edu/tudsc/2021/04/03/creating-a-3d-map-of-an-archaeological-site-in-blender/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-03T23:57:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By Elysia Petras In this blog post I explore the potential of using the 3D modeling open source software Blender for historical archaeological research. I will detail how creating a 3D map...
The post Creating a 3D Map of an Archaeological Site in Blender appeared first on Loretta C. Duckworth Scholars Studio.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elysia Petras</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transkribus at the municipal archive of the city of Bautzen]]></title>
        <id>https://readcoop.eu/?p=21819</id>
        <link href="https://readcoop.eu/transkribus-at-the-municipal-archive-of-the-city-of-bautzen/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-02T08:38:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The municipal archive of the city of Bautzen holds an extensive record of official administration from the 13th century to the present day. Council minutes are part of the main archive collections of the city archive and were almost completely digitized in 2019/2020. They can be accessed online via the Findbuch.net-platform (https://www.archivverbund-bautzen.findbuch.net/php/main.php#3632313030). However, the statistics […]
The post Transkribus at the municipal archive of the city of Bautzen appeared first on READ-COOP.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Johanna Walcher</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Humanities 2021]]></title>
        <id>588746 at https://adho.org</id>
        <link href="https://adho.org/announcements/2021/digital-humanities-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-03-30T22:50:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The annual Digital Humanities conference coordinated by ADHO will not be held in 2021. ADHO’s Constituent Organizations Board has voted to focus efforts on supporting regional conferences currently coordinated by ADHO’s Constituent Organizations and their Associate Organizations and partners. To this end, we have dedicated dh2021.adho.org to providing information about the various virtual and in-person events being hosted throughout the year.
Stay tuned for more information about DH2022, to be held in Tokyo, Japan.


Post Date: 

Tuesday, March 30, 2021]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>drupaladmin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The international Martha Cheung Award for research excellence in the paper on cross-linguistic modelling and computing received by Dr Gabriele Salciute Civiliene]]></title>
        <id>https://blogs.kcl.ac.uk/ddh/?p=3003</id>
        <link href="https://blogs.kcl.ac.uk/ddh/2021/03/29/the-international-martha-cheung-award-for-research-excellence-in-the-paper-on-cross-linguistic-modelling-and-computing-received-by-dr-gabriele-salciute-civiliene/"/>
        <updated>2021-03-29T21:20:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Gabriele Salciute Civiliene, Lecturer in Digital Humanities Education at the Department of Digital Humanities, King’s College London, has been announced the winner of the 2021 Martha Cheung Award for Best English Article in Translation Studies by the SISU Baker Centre for Translation and Intercultural Studies, Shanghai International Studies University. The Award is established in … 
Continue reading "The international Martha Cheung Award for research excellence in the paper on cross-linguistic modelling and computing received by Dr Gabriele Salciute Civiliene"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gabriele Salciute Civiliene</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ACH Executive Council 2021 Elections Results and Bylaws Updates]]></title>
        <id>https://ach.org/?p=2190</id>
        <link href="https://ach.org/blog/2021/03/26/ach-executive-council-2021-elections-results-and-bylaws-updates/"/>
        <updated>2021-03-26T15:33:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Association for Computers and the Humanities is pleased to announce the results of our 2021 elections. We had a slate of stellar candidates, and we are grateful to all the digital humanities practitioners for rising to the occasion of being nominees and willing to work at this organizational level. The 2021-25 ACH Executive Council…Continue reading.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>paigecm</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DLCL ATS round-up, winter 2021]]></title>
        <id>831 at https://digitalhumanities.stanford.edu</id>
        <link href="https://digitalhumanities.stanford.edu/dlcl-ats-round-winter-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-03-24T23:20:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Winter quarter was a time of consolidation and slow progress, without much to share by way of exciting new developments. I worked on a lot of things that I expect will bear fruit down the road, but I can't point to anything concrete yet. Here's where things stand as of spring break 2021.
Existing Projects
With some advice from Matthew Lincoln at Carnegie Mellon, I'm close to finishing the migration of the Global Medieval Sourcebook into a Jekyll site fashioned after CMU's DH Literacy Guidebook. It's been a multi-step process, including some XSLT, some Python, some OpenRefine, and I've kept notes along the way. I'm planning to write it all up during the spring, if only as a set of tips for people considering migrating from Drupal to a static website.
Thanks to the tireless nights-and-weeken…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Quinn Dombrowski</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Réponse de la SCHN/CSDH à la déclaration de la Black Canadian Studies Association]]></title>
        <id>https://csdh-schn.org/?p=702</id>
        <link href="https://csdh-schn.org/reponse-de-la-schn-csdh-a-la-declaration-de-la-black-canadian-studies-association/"/>
        <updated>2021-03-23T16:29:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Le comité exécutif et le comité de programme de la Société canadienne des humanités numériques/Canadian Society for Digital Humanities (SCHN/CSDH) sont solidaires avec la Black Canadian Studies Association (BCSA) et ...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kim Martin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSDH/SCHN Withdrawal From Congress 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://csdh-schn.org/?p=700</id>
        <link href="https://csdh-schn.org/csdh-schn-withdrawal-from-congress-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-03-23T16:28:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Executive and the Programme Committee of the Canadian Society for Digital Humanities/société canadienne des humanités numériques (CSDH/SCHN) stand in solidarity with the Black Canadian Studies Association (BCSA) and their ...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kim Martin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Behavioral Measures of Presence: Designing a VR Application]]></title>
        <id>https://sites.temple.edu/tudsc/?p=7699</id>
        <link href="https://sites.temple.edu/tudsc/2021/03/23/behavioral-measures-of-presence-designing-a-vr-application/"/>
        <updated>2021-03-23T13:53:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By Eugene Kukshinov Introduction As a part of my digital project at the Scholars studio, I am working with Dr. W. Geoffrey Wright, the director of the Motion-Action-Perception Laboratory, or MAP lab,...
The post Behavioral Measures of Presence: Designing a VR Application appeared first on Loretta C. Duckworth Scholars Studio.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Evgeny Kukshinov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Janelle Jenstad wins the 2021 Outstanding Achievement Award for Computing in the Arts and Humanities]]></title>
        <id>https://csdh-schn.org/?p=691</id>
        <link href="https://csdh-schn.org/janelle-jenstad-wins-the-2021-outstanding-achievement-award-for-computing-in-the-arts-and-humanities/"/>
        <updated>2021-03-18T13:28:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Janelle Jenstad is an Associate Professor in the Department of English at the University of Victoria. Her longest running project, the Map of Early Modern London, which she started in ...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Constance Crompton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Janelle Jenstad gagne le prix de contribution exceptionnelle de la Société canadienne des humanités numériques 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://csdh-schn.org/?p=688</id>
        <link href="https://csdh-schn.org/janelle-jenstad-gagne-le-prix-de-contribution-exceptionnelle-de-la-societe-canadienne-des-humanites-numeriques-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-03-18T13:23:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Janelle Jenstad est professeure agrégée au département d’anglais de l’Université de Victoria. Son projet de plus longue durée, la Map of Early Modern London (MoEML), qu’elle a lancé en 1999, ...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Constance Crompton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RomaJS release 0.3.1 out now!]]></title>
        <id>https://tei-c.org/?p=30957</id>
        <link href="https://tei-c.org/2021/03/16/romajs-release-0-3-1-out-now/"/>
        <updated>2021-03-16T19:57:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Raff Viglianti released RomaJS 0.3.1. For more details on bug fixes and enhancements see the release notes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martina Scholger</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Call for Applications: 2021 ADHO Communications Fellowships]]></title>
        <id>588742 at https://adho.org</id>
        <link href="https://adho.org/announcements/2021/call-applications-2021-adho-communications-fellowships"/>
        <updated>2021-03-15T11:35:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Alliance of Digital Humanities Organizations (ADHO) seeks applicants for its two 2021 Communications Fellowships, each of which comes with a stipend of €500 (Euros).
Each year, Communications Fellows work with ADHO’s Communications Officer to manage ADHO’s public communications activities. The fellowship is well suited for graduate students, young scholars, and academic professionals who wish to develop a deeper knowledge of digital humanities and its global communities, contribute to an important digital humanities scholarly and professional organization, and gain professional experience in social media and communications.
In 2021, Communications Fellows will contribute to the development of a new multilingual website for ADHO; will follow and disseminate conference information; will …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>drupaladmin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Historical GIS to Discover the Spatial and Temporal Trends of the Construction of Temples in Fujian]]></title>
        <id>https://sites.temple.edu/tudsc/?p=7615</id>
        <link href="https://sites.temple.edu/tudsc/2021/03/12/using-historical-gis-to-discover-the-spatial-and-temporal-trends-of-the-construction-of-temples-in-fujian/"/>
        <updated>2021-03-12T22:11:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By Rouying Tang I will introduce my digital project in this blog post. This project maps the trends related to temples constructed in Fujian, a Southeastern province in China. It ranges from...
The post Using Historical GIS to Discover the Spatial and Temporal Trends of the Construction of Temples in Fujian appeared first on Loretta C. Duckworth Scholars Studio.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rouying Tang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cultural Ontologies: the ArCo Knowledge Graph.]]></title>
        <id>http://openmethods.dariah.eu/?p=2878</id>
        <link href="https://openmethods.dariah.eu/2021/03/11/cultural-ontologies-the-arco-knowledge-graph/"/>
        <updated>2021-03-11T11:39:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction: Standing for 'Architecture of Knowledge', ArCo is an open set of resources developed and managed by some Italian institutions, like the MiBAC (Minister for the Italian Cultural Heritage) and, within it, the ICCD - Institute of the General Catalogue and Documentation), and the CNR - Italian National Research Council. Through the application of eXtreme Design (XD), ArCO basically consists in an ontology network comprising seven modules (the arco, the core, the catalogue, the location, the denotative description, the context description, and the cultural event) and a set of LOD data comprising a huge amount of linked entities referring to the national Italian cultural resources, properties and events. Under constant refinement, ArCo represents an example of a "robust Semantic Web resource" (Carriero et al., 11) in the field of cultural heritage, along with other projects like, just to mention a couple of them, the Google Arts&Culture (https://artsandculture.google.com/) or the Smithsonian American Art Museum (https://americanart.si.edu/about/lod).

[Click ‘Read more’ for the full post!]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marinella Testori</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Call for Nominations: 2022 Antonio Zampolli Prize]]></title>
        <id>588738 at https://adho.org</id>
        <link href="https://adho.org/announcements/2021/call-nominations-2022-antonio-zampolli-prize"/>
        <updated>2021-03-10T14:55:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Alliance of Digital Humanities Organizations (ADHO) Awards Committee is seeking nominations for the 2022 Antonio Zampolli Prize.
The Zampolli Prize is a triennial award that recognizes a single output in the field of Digital Humanities by any scholar or scholars at any stage of their career(s). As such, it offers a unique opportunity to reward individual projects that either have been formative or had a decisive impact on the field as a whole. Because the prize is awarded to the overall project, the recipients can be a single individual or a collaborative group of scholars, researchers, and/or practitioners. The output recognized can take any form: published research, developed resources, an established initiative, and/or center or tool(s) for research, for example. To be eligible for the prize, the nominated project must involve the innovative scholarly use of information and communications technologies.
We urge you, as members of the field, to take this opportunity to offer recommendations for outstanding work that you feel deserves recognition. Nominations will be accepted until 23:59 UTC on 01 September 2021. A winner will be announced during the winter of 2021-2022 and the prize will be awarded at the 2022 DH conference.
Nominations should consist of a document (1500-2000 words) describing the work to be nominated and the individual(s) involved, paying special attention to the relevance and importance of this work to the field as a whole. Please include a brief description of the work, a discussion of its innovative use of information technology and, particularly, the importance of this project to the Digital Humanities. Self-nominations will not be accepted. Please address nominations to the ADHO Awards Committee and send electronic copies to awards [at] adho [dot] org.
Note: Any previous nominations should be resubmitted.
For further information, including the terms of the award and protocols for its selection, please visit ADHO’s Zampolli Prize web page.


Post Date: 

Wednesday, March 10, 2021]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>drupaladmin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Speculative Objects: 3D Modeling of Imaginary Things]]></title>
        <id>https://sites.temple.edu/tudsc/?p=7585</id>
        <link href="https://sites.temple.edu/tudsc/2021/03/09/speculative-objects-3d-modeling-of-imaginary-things/"/>
        <updated>2021-03-09T14:26:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By Marilla Cubberley In my last blog post, I wrote about incorporating the technology at the Scholar’s Studio into my art practice and my goal of making 100 objects with both digital...
The post Speculative Objects: 3D Modeling of Imaginary Things appeared first on Loretta C. Duckworth Scholars Studio.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marilla Cubberley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Press Picker code published]]></title>
        <id>https://livingwithmachines.ac.uk/?p=1829</id>
        <link href="https://livingwithmachines.ac.uk/press-picker-code-published/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=press-picker-code-published"/>
        <updated>2021-03-08T14:04:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are very pleased to share the code for ‘Press Picker’, our interactive data visualisation tool for newspaper metadata: https://github.com/Living-with-machines/PressPicker_public. We developed Press Picker, as part of Living with Machines, to help us get a handle on British Library newspaper data, as we planned digitisation. The scale and complexity of the newspaper metadata—different formats held […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Olivia Vane</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DHNB Board 2021]]></title>
        <id>http://dig-hum-nord.eu/?p=1891</id>
        <link href="http://dhnb.eu/dhnb-board-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-03-06T03:59:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are pleased to announce the results of the DHNB Board Election. Three nominated candidates Annika Rockenberger (Norway), Mikko Tolonen (Finland), and Andres Karjus (Estonia) have been elected to serve on the DHNB Board for the period 2021–2024 starting from 10 March 2021 (full nomination statements and bios attached). The 2021 Board consist of nine […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Olga Holownia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DHNB AGM 2021]]></title>
        <id>http://dig-hum-nord.eu/?p=1893</id>
        <link href="http://dhnb.eu/agm-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-03-06T03:02:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Annual General Assembly (AGM) will be held online on on Monday, May 31 at 5 pm CET. AGM agenda will be published on our website closer to the meeting.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Olga Holownia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TEI P5 Guidelines version 4.2.1 and Stylesheets version 7.51.1 released]]></title>
        <id>https://tei-c.org/?p=30943</id>
        <link href="https://tei-c.org/2021/03/02/tei-p5-guidelines-version-4-2-1-and-stylesheets-version-7-51-1-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-03-02T08:30:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The TEI Consortium has released version 4.2.1 of the TEI P5 Guidelines and version 7.51.1 of Styelsheets, a follow-up version of the TEI P5 Guidelines version 4.2.0 and Stylesheets version 7.51.0, where we surfaced an issue with the conversion of the constraints on attributes to XHTML. This problem did not effect the schemas, but made […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martina Scholger</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Light to Physical Creation: Using Projected Light to Fabricate Real-world Structures – Part 2]]></title>
        <id>https://sites.temple.edu/tudsc/?p=7571</id>
        <link href="https://sites.temple.edu/tudsc/2021/02/28/digital-light-to-physical-creation-using-digital-light-projection-to-fabricate-real-world-structures-part-2/"/>
        <updated>2021-03-01T02:26:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By Kyle Schwab Previous Work: Prototyping a DLP 3D Printer In my previous post, I gave you a brief introduction to 3D printing and highlighted some recent advances in the field. I...
The post Digital Light to Physical Creation: Using Projected Light to Fabricate Real-world Structures – Part 2 appeared first on Loretta C. Duckworth Scholars Studio.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kyle Schwab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>